Downloaded from YTS.MX
(字幕翻译：Hardstick,校核：Hardstick，时间轴来自官译版本）
Official YIFY movies site: YTS.MX
伦敦，1890年代
-Get me a cab, will you?
-Yes, sir.
请给我叫辆马车？—是,先生
The most brilliantly written play I've seen in years.
它是这几年中我看到最精彩的戏了.
The man's a born wit.
这人真是天生奇才。
The whole play was tremendously exciting.
整剧非常令人兴奋。
I hear he's writing a new one.
听说，他正在写一部新剧。
I can hardly wait to see it.
我都等不住想看它了。
Cab!
马车！
Well, gentlemen, the English theater has just given birth to a genius.
那是，先生们，英国戏剧界诞生了一个天才。
I feel sure Wilde would be the first to agree with you, Harry.
我觉得，王尔德会首先赞同你，哈利。
I wish I could approve of the playwright as much as I approve of his play.
我会欣赏剧作家本人，就像我欣赏他的戏剧。
Who cares about him as long as he continues to give us plays like this?
只要他不断给我们呈现这样的作品，谁会在乎他本人那？
圣詹姆斯剧院隆重上演
奥斯卡 王尔德 剧着
《温德米尔夫人的扇子》
Well, Oscar, how does it feel to be a success?
那么，奥斯卡，成功的感觉如何？
Did you have any doubts, Robbie?
罗比，你没想到吧？
Congratulations, Oscar.Brilliant play! Brilliant!
祝贺你，奥斯卡，精彩的戏！太精彩了！
Ah, there I've bound to agree with you,Lord Sonning.
是的，我也这么看，桑宁爵士。
My dear Mr. Wilde, I was simply delighted with your play.
亲爱的王尔德先生，我真为你的戏剧高兴。
I even enjoyed the interval.
我甚至更享受幕间休息。
Dear Lady Sonning,she has the remains of a remarkable ugliness.
亲爱的桑宁夫人还是有着明显丑陋的剩余物。
I've always been a great admirer of your work, Mr. Wilde.
王尔德先生，我一直对您的作品报以极大的敬意。
And I've always been a great admirer of my work, Mr. Shaw.
萧先生，我也一直对我的作品报以敬意。
（萧伯纳，英国现代杰出的现实主义戏剧作家）
-Frank!-Oscar!
-弗兰克！-奥斯卡！
-Wonderful play.-Thank you.
精彩的戏。-谢谢你
-My dear lady mother.-Oscar.
-我亲爱的母亲大人。-奥斯卡
My dear boy, a triumph. A magnificent triumph.
我亲爱的孩子，一场胜利。一场伟大的胜利。
Ada, what are you going to say about my play in that woman's magazine you run?
艾达，你将在你经营的妇女杂志上怎样评价我的戏剧？
I shall praise it as highly as you would yourself, Oscar.
奥斯卡，我将会像你本人一样给它很高的赞扬。
You've always been the best critic of my work.
你一直是我作品的最好评论家。
-But I never criticize your work.-Exactly.
-但是我从未批评过你的作品。-没错。
I'm so proud, Oscar.
奥斯卡，我真为你骄傲。
And I'm so proud of you.
我也为你骄傲。
You look wonderful.
你真可爱。
Oscar, people are watching.
奥斯卡，人们都在看着呢。
I hardly think Oscar is the type of man
我很难想象奥斯卡是那种
to worry about his behavior in public.
在公众面前注重自己行为的男人。
And how did brother Willie
like the play?
怎么威利兄弟也会喜欢戏剧？
Or couldn't you see it from the bar?
你难道不是刚从从酒吧出来吗？
Ooh, I've perfectly sober,thank you, Oscar.
哦，谢谢，奥斯卡，我从未如此清醒。
I've ordered a table at the Savoy.
我在萨伏伊饭店订了一张桌子。
（它奠定了全球豪华酒店的最早标准）
OSCAR: Get a cab, Robbie,there's a good chap.    -ROBBIE: Of course.
奥斯卡：叫辆车，罗比，这是个好伙计   -罗比：当然了
Constance, you don't mind not coming.
康斯坦斯，你不想一起去吗？
-But you know,these supper parties.    -Very well, Oscar.
- 你知道的，首演庆功晚餐。   -好的，奥斯卡
-Mother will take you.Now, won't you, Mother?   -Yes, of course.
-妈妈会带上你的，是吧？妈妈    -当然喽。
-Willie, get my wrap.  -Goodbye, my dear.
-威利，拿上我的披风。   -再见，亲爱的。
Ada.
艾达。
Come along, Bosie.
跟我来，波西。
Good night, Mrs. Wilde.
晚上好，王尔德夫人。
Good night, Bosie.
晚上好，波西。
A green carnation.How delightfully eccentric.
绿色康乃馨，多逗的怪人。
Damned ridiculous,if you ask me.
要我看，那是可恶的荒唐。
But who's the handsome
young boy with him?
跟着他的那位帅哥是谁？
Good heavens, Edith,you are out of touch.
天哪，艾迪思，你一点都不晓得吗
Why, the whole of London is talking about them.
难怪，全伦敦都在谈论他们。
It's a damn disgrace the way the fellow is carrying on.
这对同伴的行事方式令人诅咒和不齿。
These artistic fellows think they can get away with anything.
这两艺术伙伴以为他们可以抛开世人的一切。
But who is he? Well, you...
他是谁？你。。。
He's Lord Alfred Douglas.Queensberry's son.
他是阿尔佛雷德 道格拉斯爵士。昆斯博里大人的儿子。
If I were Queensberry, I've...
如果我是昆斯博里，我会。。。
You've do what, sir?What would you do?
你会做什么？你要做什么？
What would you do?
你要做什么？
Excuse me.
让一下。
Lord Alfred, you remember my daughter?
阿尔弗雷德爵士，您还认识我女儿吗？
-Oh, Mrs. Somers.How do you do?-Phyllis.
-噢，索摩斯夫人，你好啊？-菲利斯
Poor Mrs. Somers.
可怜的索摩斯夫人
Still trying to get that daughter off her hands.
还想着把她女儿推销出去。
Well, she's wasting her time with him.
对他来说，她是在白费力。
Oh, my lord.
哦，我的大人。
You wicked man.
你这个邪恶的人。
Bosie!
波西
Don't you even acknowledge me anymore?
你不认我了吗？
What do you want, Father?
你想干什么，父亲？
Have you any idea how sick it makes me
你知道我有多恶心吗？
to watch you making a fool of yourself?
看到你在对你自己做傻事
A fine spectacle you are, sir,fawning and crawling round this fellow, Wilde,
真够丢人现眼的，一个勋爵，居然居然奉承巴结在这个王尔德身边，
like some damn little lapdog.
像一只可怜的哈巴狗。
Are we going to have another one of your scenes, Father?
我们能换个地点说这件事吗？父亲。
Scenes or no scenes, sir.I'd not tolerate this behavior.
管它什么场合，我不允许这种行为。
Would you sooner I went around with professional boxers and sporting gentry?
你能待会儿吗，等我去职业拳击运动俱乐部？
At least my friends behave like men.
至少我的朋友们表现像男人一样。
-Father, I'm over 21...-Only just.
-父亲，我已经21岁了。。。-刚刚。
I don't see that I have to answer to you for my behavior,
我就不明白了，为什么你要管我的事
nor seek your permission for the choice of my friends.
为什么择友还要得到你的许可。
You are a disgrace to the name of Queensberry!
你给昆斯博里家族带来耻辱
I really don't have...Bosie, is the cab ready yet?
我真的不想这样。。。波西，叫马车了吗？
Oscar, this unpleasant little man is my father.
奥斯卡，这个令人不快的人是我父亲。
-Lord Queensberry?-Yes.
-昆斯博里侯爵？-是的。
Pleasure to meet you, sir.
侯爵，很高兴认识你。
The pleasure is entirely yours,Mr. Wilde.
那是你高兴，王尔德先生
-Oscar, let's go.-Just a minute.
-奥斯卡，我们走吧。-等等
-I have a few things to say to this gentleman.-Father!
-我有一些话要向这位先生说。-父亲！
-You listen to me, sir.-Oh, really, Lord Queensberry.
-你给我听好了，先生。-哦，是的，昆斯博里侯爵。
I think the public have had enough play acting for one night.
在晚上，每个人都都演自己的自由。
I demand to be heard!
你给我听着！
You are being heard, sir,by the entire theater.I should...
听着呢，侯爵，我想全剧院的人也都听着那。。。
Well done, Wilde.
干不错啊，王尔德。
Most entertaining.We both thought so,didn't we, my dear?
太有趣了，我们都这么认为，不是吗？亲爱的。
You're very flattering,Your Royal Highness.
您过奖了，殿下( 此时的威尔士亲王，后来的爱德华七世国王）
And Mrs. Langtry,you're very beautiful.
兰格夫人，您真漂亮。（演员，也是威尔士亲王的情人）
I adore flattery almost as much as you do, Oscar.
奥斯卡，我和你一样喜欢被过奖。
I didn't know you were a patron of the arts, Queensberry.
我还真不知道你也是一个艺术的热心者，昆斯博里。
I thought fist fighting was more in your line.
我原以为你只会拳击比赛。
（第八代昆斯博里侯爵是现代拳击运动规则创始人）
Well, thank you for a most enjoyable evening, Wilde.
那么，感谢你带来的愉快夜晚，王尔德。
We shall look forward to the next play.
我们期待你下一部大作。
Good night, sir.
再见，大人。
You coming, Bosie?
你来吗？波西。
Let me just say this, Father.You're been hounding me long enough.
父亲，我受够了你像猎狗一样追我。
If you try and interfere with me again,
如果你再试着这样干涉我，
or write anymore of your abusive letters,
或者发出那些骂人的信件，
I shall have no hesitation in seeking the protection of the law.
我将不得不寻求法律的保护。
You may have the law on your hands much sooner than you think, my boy.
制裁你的法律会来的比你想得要早，小子。
Good morning, Edward.
早上好，爱德华。
Good morning, Mr. Wilde, sir.Lovely morning.
早上好，王尔德先生，多好的早晨。
Yes, I think I'll walk a little. Follow.
是的，我正打算走一段路，跟着我吧。
Where to, sir?
去哪里？先生。
The Cafe Royal.
皇家咖啡馆。
Cafe Royal? Very good, sir.
皇家咖啡馆，好的，先生。
Mr. Wilde. Mr. Wilde, sir.
王尔德先生，王尔德先生，先生。
Mr. Wilde, one thing my readers are anxious to learn.
王尔德先生，有件事我的读者们急切想知道。
-What paper do you write for, sir?-The Echo,sir.
-你是哪家报社的？ -回声报，先生。
Well, if your readers were anxious to learn anything,
那么，您的读者想知道的任何事情
they wouldn't take the Echo.
无需通过回声。
May I ask you, sir,why do you always wear a green carnation?
我能问您一下吗？先生，为什么您总戴一朵绿色康乃馨？
REPORTER: Mr. Wilde,your book Dorian Gray...
记者：王尔德先生，您的书《道林 格雷的肖像》。。。
Wait a minute. What did you say, sir?
等一下，你说什么？先生。
Why do you always wear a green carnation?
您为什么总戴一朵绿色康乃馨？
I consider nature to be quite inadequate.
因为我认为我的自然天性总是不足。
Why she never thought of a green carnation,I can't imagine.
为什么她从不考虑绿色康乃馨，我不能想象。
REPORTER: Mr. Wilde.No doubt she will get around to it in time.
记者：王尔德先生，无疑她是想及时绕开它。
Mr. Wilde, your book Dorian Grayhas been severely criticized.
王尔德先生，您的作品《道林 格雷的肖像》已经被严肃地批评了。
Not by me.
不是被我。
Yes, but, many people do consider it immoral.
是的，但是，许多人认为它不道德。
Ah, now, sir.What is immorality? I consider that to conform
告诉我，先生，什么是不道德？难道一定要迎合
to the narrow moral standards of this Victorian age
维多利亚时代狭隘的道德规范
the grossest form of immorality.
来统称什么是不道德吗
Yes, but, you know,it is said, sir,
是的，但是，您知道，大家都说
that much of your writing and indeed your basic philosophy
你写的书和您本人基本哲学思想
is fundamentally immoral.What have you to say to that?
根本就是不道德，您对此有什么好说的？
I may have offended some people,
我可能已经得罪了很多人，
but I'm sure that in 50 years,
但我敢肯定，50年后，
the works of Oscar Wilde
will be standard literature
奥斯卡王尔德的作品会是文学上的标杆
for every fifth form schoolboy.
对于每五年制小学生来说。
Hear! Hear!
有理！有理！
My only regret is that I shan't be there
我的遗憾是，那时我将不在人世了
-to collect the royalties.
-不能去收取版税了。
I must say I hardly think a newspaperman
我必须说，我不认为报纸记者
is in a position to speak of immorality.
具有评价是否道德的资格。
-What? -Indeed, Lord Alfred.
-什么？ -其实，阿尔弗雷德勋爵。
Well, what could be more immoral than a newspaper?
看吧，还有什么比报纸更不道德？
It condemns gambling on the front page
它们在头版谴责赌博
and prints racing tips on the back.
却在后版刊登赛马提示。
Brilliant, Bosie. I wish I've said that.
好极了，波西，我希望我也能说出你这样的话。
You will, Oscar. You will.
你会的，奥斯卡，你会的。
When you go back to Oxford,you can say you outwitted Oscar Wilde.
当你回到牛津，你就能说你以机制取胜了奥斯卡王尔德。
If I ever go back,I certainly will.
如果还能我回去，我当然会的。
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
Well, didn't you know? I've been sent down.
我被劝退了。（牛津大学墨德琳学院）
Congratulations!
恭喜！
All the best people are being sent down these days.
这年头，所有的好人都被劝退了。
What did you do, Bosie? Set fire to the dean's trousers?
你做什么了？把院长的裤子烧了？
Waiter! Waiter! More champagne.
侍者！侍者！再来瓶香槟。
Frankly I believe too much education's a bad thing.
坦率地说，我相信教育有很多弊端。
Don't you agree, Oscar?
这你赞同吧，奥斯卡
I certainly do.
我当然赞同。
Ignorance is a delicate blossom. Touch it and it has gone.
愚昧无知是一朵娇嫩的花朵，如你触碰它一下，它就凋谢了。
You didn't tell me that you've been sent down.
你怎么不告诉我，你被劝退了。
-Didn't I? -No.
-我没有吗？ -是的
-Oh. -Why?
-噢。 -为什么？
It was all rather tedious.
它太沉闷乏味了。
Tedious or not, I've like to hear about it.
不管是否沉闷，我都想听听。
Well, there was some scandal over a boy in the town.
好吧，有一些关于城里男孩的丑闻。
You know how provincial Oxford can be in some ways.
你知道，牛津校方对这方面一直很野蛮偏见。
Frankly, I find the whole thing rather amusing,
坦率地说，我认为整件事很好玩。
but unfortunately my father didn't.
不幸的是，我父亲不这么看。
He was so disgusted with his "so called son" as he put it,
他厌恶他的“所谓的儿子”，于是
that he's disowned me completely.
他和我断绝了关系。
So now, I haven't a penny in the world.
现在，我在这个世界上就没有一便士。
MAN: Frank, you've drunk.
男人：弗兰克，你喝醉了。
FRANK: Drunk? Who's drunk?
弗兰克：醉了？谁醉了？
Oscar, have you ever seen me when I had more than I could carry?
奥斯卡，你以前看到过我喝下去这么多吗？
No, but I've seen you when you should have taken more than one trip.
没有，但是我看到你出去（方便）了不止一次。
Why didn't you tell me about this before?
为什么你不告诉我这些？
Well, you were so busy, what, with your play and...
你总是很忙，忙剧本，忙其他。。。
If you've in any trouble, you only have to come to me.
如果你有什么困难，请来找我。
And if it's money you need,you needn't worry.
你不要担心钱的事情
You've very kind to me, Oscar.
你对我太好了，奥斯卡。
I'm very fond of you.
我非常喜欢你。
Besides, what is friendship for?
再说，友谊是用来做什么的？
Come on, Mr. Wilde, we're running out of conversation.
来吧，王尔德先生，我们已经没得好聊了。
As long as we've not running out of wine.
只要我们还没有喝完酒
Waiter! Waiter!
侍者！侍者！
You know, gentlemen, in the past few years,
先生们，在过去几年中，
I've made a remarkable discovery.
我有一个惊人的发现。
What was that, Oscar?
什么呀？奥斯卡。
Alcohol, if taken in sufficient quantities,
酒精，只要喝个够
produces all the effects of intoxication.
就能产生所有陶醉的效果。
Gentlemen, I give you a toast.
先生们，我提议干杯。
To youth.
致青春。
HARRIS: Oscar, you talk as if you're an old man.
哈里斯：奥斯卡，你说这话感觉你是一个老人。
I am. I'll do anything to regain my lost youth
我是，我将努力找回所逝去的青春
except take up exercise or get up early in the morning.
除了锻炼或早起
Waiter! Waiter, where’s that champagne?
侍者！侍者，我们点香槟呢？
MAN: Ah, thank you. Here we are.
男人：啊。谢谢你，我们在这。
-Good evening, sir. -Hello, Arthur.
-晚上好，先生。 -好。阿瑟。
Oscar! You said you'll be in for lunch.
奥斯卡，你说过午饭时回来的。
Yes, I had a meeting with my publisher.
是的，我会见了我的出版人。
The children have been asking for you.
孩子们一直在问你。
OSCAR: Oh.
奥斯卡：哦。
They refuse to go to sleep until you tell them a story.
你不回来给他们讲故事，他们就不睡觉。
Oh, very well.
哦，好吧。
BOYS: Daddy! Daddy!
男孩们：爸爸！爸爸！
Now, what's all this about your not sleeping?
你们怎么都不睡啊？
We want you to tell us a story.
我们想让你讲故事。
I see.
我知道了，
Well, now, what shall I tell you tonight about?
那么，今晚上讲个什么呢？
Not too long, Oscar.
别太长了，奥斯卡。
Giants or dragons?
巨人或者怪龙？
You told us the story about giants last night.
您昨天晚上讲的是巨人。
Well, have I told you the story about the Happy Prince?
那么，我给你们讲过快乐王子的故事吗？
No.
不
High above the city on a tall column
在城市耸立着高柱上
stood the statue of the Happy Prince.
站着快乐王子的塑像。
He was gilded all over with thin leaves of fine gold.
他浑身镀有薄薄一层精致的金箔。
For eyes he had two bright sapphires
他有两只像蓝宝石一样的眼睛
and a large red ruby glowed on his sword hilt.
他剑柄上镶嵌的红宝石闪闪发光。
He was as beautiful as a weather cock.
他像风向标一样美丽。
Yes, sir?
您是？先生，
Mr. Oscar Wilde?
王尔德先生在家吗？
I don't know that he's at home, sir.
我不知道，先生
Ah. My name is Wood.
啊。我是伍德。
-Wood, sir? -Yes.
-您是伍德？  -是的
I'm a friend of Lord Alfred Douglas.
我是阿尔弗雷德 道格拉斯爵士的朋友。
Oh, I see, sir. Would you step inside, sir?
哦，我知道了，您请进屋吧，先生？
I'll enquire if Mr. Wilde will see you, sir.
我去问一下，王尔德能否见您，先生。
"Dear little swallow," said the prince.
“可爱的小麻雀”王子说。
"You tell me marvelous things,
“请告诉我一些不可思议的事情，
"but more marvelous than anything
“最不可思议的事情是
"is the suffering of men and women."
“男人们和女人们正在受苦。”
Excuse me, sir.There's a person to see you, sir.
对不起，有位先生来看您。
Very well.
好吧。
-He gave his name as Wood, sir.  -Wood?
-他说他名叫伍德。 -伍德？
Said he was a friend of Lord Alfred's , sir.
并说他是阿尔弗雷德勋爵的朋友。
Oh, I see.
哦，我知道了。
He's in the front room, sir.
他在客厅等候，先生。
Thank you, Arthur.
谢谢，阿瑟。
Mr. Wood?
伍德先生？
That's right, sir.
正是，先生。
Oh. Very delicate. Very delicate indeed.
噢，太精致了，真的很精致。
I understand you are a friend of Lord Alfred's.
您是阿尔弗雷德爵士的朋友？
Uh, well, I suppose you might say that, sir, yes.
恩,我猜您会这么说,先生,是的.
A very friendly gentleman, His Lordship, sir, very friendly.
一个非常友善的人,爵士,他是非常友善的.
Well, he didn't mention you, Mr. Wood, but...
伍德先生,他可没有提及过您...
Uh, Alfred Wood, sir.
哈,阿尔弗雷德 伍德,先生
Same name as His Lordship, sir.
我和爵士同名
I'm no lord, of course, sir,
我当然没有爵士头衔,先生,
but as a poet like yourself might say, "What's in a name?"
但正如您自己的诗句中所说“什么是名头？”
Cognac, Mr. Wood?
白兰地，伍德先生？
Thank you, sir.
谢谢您
You knew Lord Alfred at Oxford?
您知道阿尔弗雷德爵士在牛津的事情吗？
Well, not exactly at Oxford, sir.
不是特别清楚，先生
No, sir, not in the way that you might mean.
不，先生，不是你指的那方面的事。
I used to do odd jobs for His Lordship.
我曾经给爵士做一些特别的工作
Oh, very kind he was to me, sir. Yes.
他对我很好，先生，是的。
A gentleman like yourself, sir, in every particular.
和您一样的绅士，一模一样。
Thank you, sir. Well, I'm very glad to meet any friend of Bosie's.
谢谢，我很乐意见波西的朋友
Bosie?
波西？
Oh.
哦
Yes, of course, sir.
当然了，先生
Your health, sir.
祝你健康
Very fine brandy this, sir. Drives the cold from the bones.
很好的白兰地，先生，一下子暖和起来了。
Well, I, uh...
那么，我，恩。。。
I won't beat about the bush, sir, as the saying goes.
我就不兜圈子了，先生，正如您说的
Quite by accident, sir, I assure you, I a...
非常偶然的，先生，我向您保证，我 一个。。。。
I came across that letter from you to Lord Alfred Douglas.
我发现了一封您写给道格拉斯爵士的信
Very beautiful letter, if I might say so, sir.
一封非常漂亮的信，请允许我这么说，先生。
Only I think that perhaps
我认为，可能其中
there are parts that could be "misconstrued," I think is the word, sir.
有些部分，在语句上会引起“误会”，先生
How did you come by this?
你是怎么得到它的？
Ah, yes, well, I used to...
啊。是的，我曾经。。。
Used to press Lord Alfred's clothes.
给阿尔弗雷德爵士熨烫衣物。
Very particular about his clothes, sir.
是那种非常特殊的衣物，先生。
As well you may know.
您知道的。
I, uh, found it in one of his pockets.
我，恩，我在他口袋里发现它的
Are you asking me to purchase my own work, Mr. Wood?
伍德先生，你是想让我赎回我自己的作品吗？
Well, sir, I... Come, sir, that's not very sound economics.
那么，先生，我。。。说吧，这也没什么不好意思的。
Well, I've already been offered 60pound for it, sir.
先生，我已经为它付了60英镑。
Then I suggest that you sell it at once.
那我建议你还是马上把他卖给别人吧。
I myself have seldom been offered so much
我自己不会花这么多钱
for a prose work of that length.
为了这么一篇小散文。
You take the letter, sir.
那你还是把信拿回去吧。先生。
It was stupid of me to try and rent you.
我真愚蠢，和您讨价还价。
The thing is, sir, that I'm desperate for money and...
可事实上，我已经在经济上很拮据了
A hungry man gets driven to do stupid things.
一个饥饿的人干出这样的傻事。
Oh, would you like a ham sandwich?
哦，你需要一个火腿三明治吗？
Now you've making fun of me, sir.
先生，你拿我取笑了。
On the contrary, Mr. Wood.
相反，伍德先生。
You've doing remarkably well yourself.
你已经表现的非常好。
Well, I think I'll be going now, sir.
我想我该走了，先生。
No, no, no, no. Please stay and finish your drink.
不不不，请再呆一会，喝完酒再走。
That's very kind of you.
您真是太好了。
You're a very poor criminal, Mr. Wood, if I may say so.
伍德先生，你是个可怜的罪犯，我能这么说吧。
The fact is I came to London to look for some work.
实际上，我是到伦敦找工作的。
Ah, work, Mr. Wood, is the curse of the drinking classes.
啊，伍德先生，工作，它是酒徒们的咒语。
The secret of maintaining youth
保持青春的秘诀是
is an inordinate passion for pleasure.
尽情享受快乐。
40pounds, sir?
40英镑,先生?
I'm going out to dine in a moment. Perhaps you shoud not care to join me.
我一会儿要去吃晚餐,也许你不介意和我一起.
Well, that's very kind of you, sir.
您真是太客气了,先生.
There's a fascinating charm
你的犯罪意识里有一种
about your halfhearted criminal tendencies, Mr. Wood.
不刻意的迷人的魅力,伍德先生.
I suspect that you lead a wonderfully wicked life.
我猜想你一定过着非常的邪恶生活。
Ah, well, there's good and bad in all of us, sir.
啊，我们每个人都有好的一面和坏的一面。
Mr. Wood, you're a born philosopher.
伍德先生，您是一个天生的哲学家。
I'm sure we shall get along extremely well.
我保证我们一定会聊得很投机。
Your health, sir.
祝您健康，先生。
Shall I serve dinner, madam?
夫人，需要我布置晚餐吗？
I can't understand it. I'm sure Mr. Wilde said
我真不明白了，我肯定王尔德先生说过
he would be in for dinner.
他将回来吃晚餐
Well, perhaps he's been detained on business, madam.
也许他被生意上的事耽搁了，夫人。
Yes.
是的
Shall we wait?
我们等他吗？
No, Arthur, I'll dine alone.
不了，阿瑟，我自己一个人吃吧。
Very well, madam.
好的，夫人。
Bosie, you're nearly an hour late.
波西，你晚了一个小时。
Yes, I know.
我知道。
Oh, I know what that face means.
噢，我知道你那张脸意味着什么。
It usually heralds an unpleasant scene.
一般来说，它意味着不高兴的场景。
It would be nice if it could be avoided.
如果能避免将会好起来
I'm in a singularly good mood.
我的心情将会非常好起来。
-Are you?  -I was.
-你是吗？  -我是。
No doubt, having entertained your friend at the Savoy last night.
毫无疑问，你昨晚肯定在萨伏伊酒店让你的朋友很高兴。
You mean Mr. Wood?
你是说伍德先生？
Really, Oscar, have you no sense of propriety?
真的，奥斯卡，你就不能说得体一点吗？
The man is a valet.
那人是个男仆。
A very amusing valet.
一个非常有趣的男仆。
Thank heavens, Bosie, I am not inhibited by your sense of class.
天呐，波西，我受不了你的阶级优越感。
So it seems.
看来是的。
Anyway, he was your friend.
不管怎样，他曾是你的朋友。
I hardly knew the man.
我几乎不熟悉他。
That's not the impression that he gave to me.
他没有给我留下什么印象。
WAITER: Good morning, My Lord.
侍者：上午好，大人。
What did he want anyway?
他到底想要什么？
Money. What do the poor usually want?
钱。穷人们都想要的？
Would you like to order now, My Lord?
您想点餐吗？大人。
And you gave it to him?
那你给他了？
For a valuable piece of property.
一大笔钱。
A letter I wrote you at Oxford.
你在牛津时我给你写的信。
WAITER: May I recommend the lobster, My Lord?
侍者：大人。我能向您推荐龙虾吗？
-I'll have the sole meuniere. -Very good.
-我想要单独裹面粉的。  -好的。
Do you mean he blackmailed you?
你是说他敲诈你了？
Leaving that letter around for anyone to find was not only careless of you,
把那封信放到任何人可以得到它的地方，这不仅仅是你的粗心大意，
but singularly lacking in respect
而是非常缺乏尊重
for something that I'd hoped was private and personal.
那可是我希望保留的隐私
Waiter, bring some champagne right away.
侍者，来瓶香槟，快点。
Very good, My Lord.
好的，大人。
It's seem, Bosie, that I am forever paying
你看，波西，我一直为你的
for your indiscretions and your extravagances.
轻率和奢侈支付。
Money, is that all you ever think of?
钱，这不是你以前一直想的吗？
Ah, when I was young I thought money was everything.
啊，在我年轻时，认为金钱万能。
Now that I'm older I know that it is.
现在我老了，还是这么想。
My God, Oscar, you've never satisfied.
上帝，奥斯卡，你从来没有满足过。
You have a successful book out,
你的书卖得很成功，
a play running in the West End...
一部在西区（伦敦富人区）剧院演出的剧作。。。
Playing to packed houses of creditors.
可舞台下却挤满了我的债主。
Have you any idea how much money I've spent since we've been together?
你知道，自从你我在一起，我花了多少钱吗？
I'm sure you've kept an account.
我想你有一个账单。
Luncheon every day here, dinner at the Savoy, supper at...
午餐在这里，晚餐在萨伏伊，夜宵在。。。
-Oh, look what you've done.  -I'm sorry, sir.
-噢，你怎么回事。 -对不起，大人。
-Please.  -Oh, go away, stop fussing.
-请。  -走开吧，别再添乱了。
And always the best champagne
而且总是上等香槟
because you have a very delicate palate.
因为你的口味很刁。
Bosie, you seem to think that you have a right to live at my expense
波西，你有权靠我的花费过着
in a profuse luxury to which you have never been accustomed.
毫不吝惜的奢侈，那种你从未习惯的生活。
I pay your hotel bills, your tailor's bill,
我付了你的旅馆账单，你的裁缝账单，
your gambling debts.
还有你的赌债。
You demand without grace and you receive without thanks.
你不客气地索取，却对获得毫无感激。
Have you finished?
你有完没完？
Now tell me honestly, Oscar. What did you expect, hmm?
说真的，奥斯卡，你到底想要什么？
Did you think I was some common street Arab
你是不是把我当成普通街头的流浪儿
to be bought with cheap trinkets
可以被廉价的小玩意收买
and an occasional supper in some Soho restaurant?
或者感念你偶尔在苏荷区（伦敦小吃街）的饭馆请我几顿晚餐？
I've given you my friendship for two years, Oscar.
奥斯卡，两年来，我付出了我的友谊。
I've admired your genius, laughed at your jokes, flattered your vanity.
我倾慕你的天才，会意你的笑话，迎合你的虚荣。
And now you question the price of such a friendship.
而现在你却质疑这种友谊的价钱。
It isn't worthy of you, Oscar.
为你不值得，奥斯卡。
给我的波西
奥斯卡赠
于1893年圣诞
-Good evening, Mr. Wilde.  -Evening, William.
-晚上好，王尔德先生。  -好，威廉。
Sydney.
西德尼。
Thank you, sir.
在，先生。
-Good evening, Mr. Wilde. -Good evening.
-晚上好，王尔德先生。  -好。
I want you to take this to this address.
我想让你把它送到这个地址。
It's just around the corner.
它离这不远。
-Straight away, hmm?  -Right away, sir.
-直接去，好吧?  -马上，先生。
Hello, Robbie.
你好，罗比。
Hello, Oscar.
你好，奥斯卡。
What will you have?
喝点什么？
Brandy, and a large one.
白兰地，大杯的。
John. A large brandy.
约翰，大杯白兰地。
Give me a cigarette, there's a dear fellow.
给我根烟吧，伙计。
I seem to have left mine at home.
我好像把它落在家了。
-What?  -A cigarette.
-什么？  -来根烟。
Oh, yes, of course.
哦，当然可以。
Thank you.
谢谢
What is it, Oscar?  Are you not well?
怎么了，奥斯卡，不舒服吗？
No, just very tired, that's all.
没有，就是有点累。
Your brandy, sir.
您的白兰地，先生。
Thank you.
谢谢
Oscar, did you know that some of the club members
奥斯卡，你知道吗？俱乐部的一些会员
have approached the Committee to get you to resign?
想让委员会劝你退会？
Well, I hope not. I shall have to find somewhere else
我可不希望，我还想找个地方
to sleep in the afternoons.
在下午睡一觉。
Have you any idea how much people are talking about you
你知道别人都在谈论你吗？
or what they are saying?
想知道他们都说了些什么吗？
I adore scandal about other people,
我非常想知道别人的绯闻，
but about myself I find it extremely dull.
而我自己的，确是很枯燥的。
It hasn't the charm of novelty.
它没什么新奇的魅力。
I don't think you'll find this gossip dull.
我不觉得这些谣言很无聊枯燥。
Robbie, are you being solicitous about my welfare?
罗比，你能让我清净一会吗？
That is very impertinent of you.
你这样很无理。
I don't mean to be.
我不是这个意思。
Oscar, I realize that much of your extravagant behavior
奥斯卡，我觉得你有很多过份的举动
is done purely for effect. You've an artist.
纯粹是为了效果，因你是一个艺术家。
The public expects you to be different.
但公众希望你等够表现不同。
But you've no longer an ascetic young poet just down from Oxford.
你已经不是一个从牛津来的，苦兮兮的年轻诗人。
-Relax.  -You're a highly successful playwrighter
-行了吧。  -你现在是一个很成功的作家
at the peak of your career.
正处在事业顶峰。
You dine with royalty. You mix in the highest social circles.
你和皇室一起用晚宴，你和社会上层圈子打交道。
Ah.
啊
You're walking along a precipice, Oscar.
你现在正走在悬崖边上，奥斯卡。
Just as long as you continue to play court jester,
只要你继续为宫廷提供娱乐，
society will accept you.
（上流）社交界就会接受你。
But tax their tolerance too far
但如果你向他们征收更多的容忍
and they'll send you crashing from the heights
那他们将把你从高处彻底击碎
-to the depths of obscurity.  -Oh, really.
-把我打回默默无闻的深渊。  -哦，真的。
A halo doesn't have to fall very far, Oscar, to become a noose.
光环不久就会变成套索落下，奥斯卡。
Really, Robbie, this all very tedious.
真的，罗比，这也太无聊了。
Just tell me one thing.
你只要告诉我一件事。
These stories I hear about you.
那些我听到的关于你的绯闻
There isn't any truth in them, is there?
没有一点是真的，是不是？
As I don't know what the stories are,
我都不这道那些绯闻是什么，
I'm hardly in a position to answer you.
我不知该如何回答你。
They say that you...
他们说你。。。
You're being blackmailed because of your association with Bosie.
你因和波西交往而被人敲诈。
That you consort with criminals, stable boys.
你和罪犯打交道，那个马夫。
This sounds all very exciting and intriguing.
这听起来又刺激又有趣。
Do go on.
接着说。
I just want to hear you tell me it isn't true.
我只想听你说这不是真的。
Robbie,
罗比，
I'm deeply hurt that you use our friendship to pry into my private life.
你有我们的友谊来刺探我个人的生活，对此我感到很受伤。
I thought you were a gentleman. I now see that you are not.
我过去认为你是一个绅士，现在我不这么认为。
I just want to hear you deny it, Oscar.
我只想听你否认它，奥斯卡。
You must think what you will, Robbie.
你爱怎么想就怎么想，罗比。
Mr. Wood to see you, sir.
先生，有位伍德先生想见您。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Robbie, because I'm very fond of you
罗比，因为我很喜欢你
I shall forget everything you've said tonight.
我将忘掉刚才你跟我说的一切。
Good night.
晚安
Hello, Oscar.
你好，奥斯卡。
Lovely club you've got here.
您的这个俱乐部很不错啊。
-I like that.
-我喜欢它。
I'd like some champagne tonight.
我今晚想喝点香槟。
Oh, you shouldn't have bothered.
哦，进来吧。
You must eat something.
你得吃点东西了。
All right?
好吧？
You know, I've eaten in all of the best restaurants in Europe
你知道，我吃遍了全欧洲最好的餐馆
but I've never tasted anything like your sweetbreads.
没有一家能做出你这样好吃的甜面包。
Where's the wine?
红酒呢？
They didn't deliver any this week.
这周酒商没有送来。
For heaven's sake, why not?
天呐，为什么？
Perhaps the fact that we owe the wine merchant 85 pounds
事实上，我们已经欠了酒商85英镑。
might have something to do with it.
这件事该认真对待了。
We've living on credit, Oscar, and that can't go on much longer.
我在靠信用过活，奥斯卡，再也不能这样下去了。
Well, if I can finish this play, everything will be all right.
等我这部戏写完，一切都会解决的。
If that's Bosie, tell him I'm not at home.
如果是波西，告诉她我不在家。
QUEENSBERRY: I wish to see Mr. Oscar Wilde.
昆斯博里：我希望见到奥斯卡 王尔德先生。
ARTHUR: I'm sorry, sir, but Mr. Wilde is not at home.
阿瑟：对不起，先生，王尔德先生不在家。
Well, I'm sorry, but I demand to see him.
那就对不起了，我必须要见到他。
You can't go in there, sir.
先生，你不能进去。
If you please, sir.
客气点，先生。
Wilde, I want to have a word with you. Sit down.
王尔德，我要跟你说几句话，你坐下。
Well, Lord Queensberry. It's all right, Arthur, you can go.
好吧，昆斯博里侯爵，可以，阿瑟，你们走吧。
It seems the peerage don't have a monopoly of good manners.
看来，礼貌也并不是贵族的专利。
To hell with good manners, sir.
让礼貌见鬼去吧，先生
What I have to say to you has very little to do with good manners.
我不得不跟你说的，与礼貌毫无关系。
Indeed? And I presume you've brought your ugly friend
事实上，我猜你带来的丑陋朋友
to lend you moral support.
已经给你带来道义上的支持。
When it comes to morals, I have all the support I need,
说到道义，我已经得到了我需要的各种支持，
thank you very much.
非常感谢您。
I've seldom come across anybody in whom the moral sense was dominant
我很少对那些有明显的
who was not heartless, cruel, vindictive and completely lacking
无情，残忍，凶恶相貌的人产生道德感，并认为他们完全缺少
in the smallest sense of humanity, Lord Queensberry.
最起码的人性，昆斯博里侯爵。
Personally, I've sooner have 50 unnatural vices
就个人而言，我将马上拥有50个后天的恶习
than one unnatural virtue.
而不是一个天生的美德。
Yes, I can well believe that. Now, you listen to me, sir.
是的，我非常相信这点。现在，你给我听好了，先生。
I presume you have come to make a speech.
我猜你是来做一个演讲的。
If so, I hope it's a short one because I have work to do.
如果那样，我希望您快点，因我还有工作要做。
Wilde.
王尔德。
I've come here today to protest against
我今天来这里是向你抗议，反对
your disgusting relationship with my son.
你和我儿子之间的令人作呕的关系。
That is a revolting and slanderous statement,
这是令人厌恶和造谣中伤的陈述，
and I demand an apology.
我要你道歉。
I refuse to apologize.
我拒绝道歉。
I refuse to apologize for saying something which is common knowledge
我拒绝道歉，因为我说的这些话会让
to every cab driver and messenger boy in London.
伦敦任何一个马车夫或送信童都有同感。
Lord Queensberry, are you seriously suggesting that
昆斯博里侯爵，你难道不是认真地暗示
there is improper conduct between your son and myself?
你儿子和我之间有不正当的关系吗？
I do not say that you are.
我没有说你是这样的。
I say that you look it, which is just as bad.
我说你要看到，这会坏到什么地步。
But I'll tell you this.
但我要告诉你这些。
If I catch you two again together,
如果我再看到你两人在一起，
I shall take a whip to you, sir, and I shall thrash you to the ground.
我将拿鞭子抽你，直到把你抽倒在地上。
I see that when it comes to fighting,
要打架就来吧，
you choose to ignore the Queensberry rules.
你可以选择不顾及你的昆斯博里规则（拳击规则，倒地15秒认输）
-Yes, well, I give you fair warning.  -And I give you fair warning.
-是的，我给你公平的警告。  -我也要给你公平的警告。
If you've not out of my house in two minutes, I shall throw you out.
如果你两分钟内不离开我的房间，我将把你扔出去。
I refuse to leave until I've had my say.
我不说完我不会离开的。
On the contrary, sir, you are leaving now.
正相反，先生，现在你就给我离开。
Hit him! Hit him!
揍他！揍他！
Arthur, open the door! This gentleman is leaving.
阿瑟，开门，这位先生要出去。
Gladly, sir.
好的，先生。
This, Arthur, is the Marquis of Queensberry.
这位，阿瑟，是昆斯博里第八代侯爵。
The most infamous brute in London and you've never to let him in my house again.
这个伦敦最臭名昭着的畜生，你不能让他再进我的家门。
-Is that clear?   -Perfectly, sir.
-明白了吗？  -完全明白，先生。
Now get out.
现在滚吧。
Very well.
非常好。
But you'll regret this, I promise you.
我保证你会后悔的。
I promise you.
我发誓
Go back to your room this instant.
马上会回你们的房间。
Will that be all, sir?
这就结束了吧？先生。
I hope so, Arthur.
我希望是，阿瑟。
Now, this has got to stop.
现在，该阻止这些事情再发生了。
You are the only one who can stop it, Oscar.
你是唯一能阻止这些事情的人，奥斯卡。
My God, am I not allowed to get on with my work in peace?
上帝啊，我到底能不能安静地工作?
What with creditors knocking at the door
如果是债主敲门怎么办
and Bosie dropping in as if this was some sort of club.
如果是波西或者俱乐部其他人拜访怎么办。
And now this coarse brute with his hired pugilists.
而现在是那些粗鄙的恶棍和他所雇佣的打手。
I can stand brute force, but brute reason is quite intolerable.
我能抵抗畜生的力量，但是畜生的理智却让人不能忍受。
It's like hitting below the intellect.
就像打击弱智的人。
Oscar, I beg of you to give up this friendship with Bosie.
奥斯卡，我希望你放弃和波西的友谊。
Not for me, but for your own sake.
不是为了我，而是为你自己。
He takes up too much of your time,
他占用了你太多的时间，
demands too much of your emotions.
剥夺了你太多的情感。
I know.
我知道。
The truth is the boy has a strange fascination for me
事实上，这男孩对我有奇怪的幻想
that I can't get free of.
而我又不能抛弃他。
He needs you more than you need him.
他对你的要求多于你对他的。
He needs you because he is weak and conceited.
它需要你，因为他的脆弱和自负。
And you give him a stature he could never acquire alone.
而你给了他一个人永远达不到的声望。
And he will go on taking and taking until there's nothing left.
他会一直拿走它，直到它什么都没剩下。
He'll destroy you, Oscar.
他会毁了你，奥斯卡。
When I married you,
当我嫁给你时，
I didn't believe it was possible to love anybody more than I loved you.
我不相信还有人比我更爱你。
I still love you, darling.
我一直爱你，亲爱的。
To me you are higher and greater than any man in the world.
对我来说，你是世界上最高尚最伟大的男人。
Help me, Constance.
帮帮我吧，康斯坦斯。
Help me.
救我。
Why not go away for a little while?
为何不暂时离开这一切呢？
At least until you have finished your play.
至少等到你写完你的剧本。
Maybe it will give you a chance to think more clearly.
也许，它会给你一个机会去想清楚这些。
Yes, I may.
是的，我会的。
You always liked the sea. Why not go down to Brighton?
你一直喜欢大海，为什么不去一趟布莱顿（英格兰西部港口）呢？
It should be very quiet at this time of year.
它将是这年中非常平静的时候。
It's a wonderful idea, Constance,
好主意，康斯坦斯，
but we've hardly enough money to pay the tradesmen, let alone hotel bills.
但是我们几乎没有足够钱来支付那些商人，更不用说旅馆账单。
I haven't touched my father's allowance for some months.
我已经有几个月没有动用过我父亲给我的津贴。
-It isn't very much, I'm afraid.   -No, no, Constance.
-它虽然不多，我恐怕。  -不，不，康斯坦斯。
Please. Please.
放心，放心。
I love you.
我爱你。
Goodness Lordy, Mr. Wilde, wherever have you been?
上帝啊，王尔德先生，你去哪里了？
I've been conversing with the elements, Mrs. Burgess.
我去和大自然谈了会儿话，伯杰斯夫人。
Oh, goodness me, you've soaked to the skin.
哦，天呐，您都湿透了。
Listening to the wisdom of the sea, Mrs. B.
我听到了大海的智慧，伯杰斯夫人。
Out all night in weather like this.
这个天气，你居然在外头呆了一晚上
Now, you come upstairs and we'll get those wet clothes off
现在赶紧上楼，把湿衣服换下来
-before you catch your death.   -It's all here.
-在你将冻死之前。   -它都装在这里了。
Every word and every epigram, Mrs. Burgess.
每一个单词和每一个警句，伯杰斯夫人。
Oh, I'm very glad, Mr. Wilde, but do come on.
哦，我很高兴，王尔德先生，但要快点脱。
Every move and every curtain.
每一次转换和每一次启幕。
It's all here.
都装在这里了。
And the important thing is who is Ernest.
重要的是，谁是欧内斯特。
(此时王尔德正在构思剧本《不可儿戏》，欧内斯特是剧中人物）
Oh, yes, that will be nice.
哦，是的，这就好了。
Ernest and his little aunt...
欧内斯特和他的小姑母。。。
But upstairs now, like a good boy, please, Mr. Wilde.
快上楼，像个乖孩子，王尔德先生。
You've very kind, Mrs. Burgess.
您太善良了，伯杰斯夫人。
Well, if we can't show a little kindness on this earth,
在这个世界上，如果我们再不表现出一点善良，
we might as well not be here, that's the way I see it.
那还是别在这里生存下去了，这是就我明白的地方。
Now, you keep nice and warm.
现在，你暖暖和和地睡个好觉。
Are you sure this is the right place, my dear chap?
你能肯定是这个地方吗？老伙计。
This is where I brung him, sir. No mistaking him.
是我带他来这里的，先生，不会有错的。
Proper artistic gentleman he was.
他就是那个风趣儿的绅士。
Just wait here, will you?
在这等一下吧
Right, sir.
行，先生。
Good morning, madam.
早上好，夫人。
Is it remotely possible you have a Mr. Oscar Wilde staying here?
一个叫奥斯卡王尔德的先生会住在您这里吗？
Why, yes, sir.
为什么不会，是的，先生。
How extraordinary.
太奇特了。
-Ah, may I step inside? -Certainly, sir.
-我能进屋吗？  -当然，先生。
Which is his room?
他住哪间房？
It's just at the top of the stairs.
楼梯顶那间。
Oh, but I'm rather you didn't disturb him, sir.
我希望您别打扰他，先生。
You see, he was out all night and he's not at all well.
你知道，他出去呆了一整夜，他现在不舒服。
Indeed?
真的？
I was wondering if I'd send for the doctor.
我正在想是否送他去医生那里。
A doctor, madam, would probably prescribe
医生，夫人，会给他开的处方是
a little less brandy in his soda.
一小杯白兰地加苏打水。
Well.
好吧。
So this is where you've been hiding yourself, hmm?
这就是你藏身的地方？
Bosie.
波西。
Really, Oscar, you are the most tedious person.
真的，奥斯卡，你是个最乏味的人。
I've been all over Brighton.
我找遍了布莱顿。
From one hotel to another,
从一家旅馆到另一家旅馆，
tracking you down like some private detective.
像私家侦探一样搜寻你。
-What do you want?  -What?
-你想干什么？  -什么
What do I want?
我想干什么？
I don't want a thing, I came to see you.
我什么都不想，我就是来看你。
Good heavens, it's so dark in here.
天呐，这里也太暗了。
Well, I must say you don't look any too good.
我必须跟你说，你的气色很不好。
Oh, yeah.
哦。是的
I think I've got a chill, I...
我想我是着凉了，我。。。
You must be out of your mind coming to a place like this.
你必须抛开躲到这里的想法。
I can't imagine what the food must be like.
我不能想象你吃得这是什么。
Of course, as soon as I knew you were in Brighton,
当然了，我一知道你到了布莱顿，
I naturally went straight to The Grand.
我就直奔大酒店。
Naturally.
自然的。
I have a most delightful suite there overlooking the sea.
我已经订了一间能看到海景的最豪华的套房。
And I shall get the bill, no doubt, in due course.
毫无疑问，到时候，我就会收到账单的。
Seriously though, Os, I won't allow you to stay
说正经的，我可不想让你
in this dreary little hovel another minute.
在这种可怜的小旅馆里再多呆一分钟。
Besides, the most fascinating people are staying at The Grand.
另外，一些奇妙的人物都呆在大酒店里。
Just look at this picture, really.
看看这些画吧，真逗。
Bosie, can't you understand
波西，你难道不明白
that I came here to finish my play in peace and quiet?
我来这里是为了平和安静地完成我的剧本（指《不可儿戏》）？
I was driven nearly frantic in London with you and your father.
我在伦敦都快被你和你父亲逼疯了。
Bosie, I've got to work.
波西，我得工作。
I'm the last person in the world to want to interfere with your work.
我可是这个世界上最后一个想干预你的作品的人。
Whether you mean it or not, you do.
不论你说的是或不是，你都这样干了。
What are you looking for?
你在找什么？
I'm looking for my handkerchief. What do you think I'm looking for?
我在找我的手帕，你以为我在找什么？
Here it is, for heaven's sake.
在这呢，天呐。
Really, Oscar, when you are ill, you've singularly unamusing.
真的，奥斯卡，当你病了的时候，你就更有魅力了。
I can't help being ill.
我可不想生病。
But you can help being a bore.
但你却能忍住令人厌烦。
Is this your new play?
这就是你的新剧本？
"The Importance of Being Earnest."
“认真的重要性”
（即《不可儿戏》）
Yes, it's nearly finished.
是的，它快完工了。
I'm glad to hear it. Poverty ill becomes you.
我很高兴听到这些。贫穷疾病成就了你。
Frankly, I think you're being very unreasonable about this whole thing.
坦率地说，我都不知道整件事情你是怎么想的。
You disappear, leaving me in town without a penny piece.
你去玩失踪，我却身无分文地被丢在城里。
Are you trying to end this relationship, Oscar?
你是想结束我俩的关系吗？奥斯卡。
Is that what you want?
这就是你要的？
I don't know what I want. I just want to be left in peace.
我不知道我要什么。我只想一个人静静地待会儿。
"Thank you for your company.
“谢谢你的陪伴。
"It was charming while it lasted. Now kindly get out."
“如果它能延续下去，那就太令人陶醉了。”
Bosie, can't you see that I'm ill and I hardly know what I'm doing?
波西，难道你没看到我病了，我都不知道我在干什么？
And what about me?
那我呢？
I don't care what you do,
我不管你怎么做，
but as long as you go away and leave me alone.
我只要你走开，让我一个人待会儿。
You mean for good?
你是说永远吗？
It can't go on, your insane tantrums and your extravagances.
再也不能这样下去了，你的疯狂暴怒和你的奢侈挥霍。
It's got to stop, Bosie.
这必须停止了，波西。
Wouldn't my father be delighted to think
这下我父亲该高兴了
he'd finally broken up our friendship?
他终于让我们断绝了关系
My God, it is stuffy in here.
上帝，这里也太闷了。
I don't know how you can breathe.
我都不知道你在这里怎么呼吸。
Once and for all, I'm sick to death of being a cat's-paw
让我一了百了地病死吧，我可不想成为
in this terrible war between you and your father.
你和你父亲之间可怕战争的牺牲品。
And for heaven's sake, close the window.
看在老天爷的份上，把窗户关上吧。
Am I to be held responsible for the ravings of my lunatic father?
我还需要为我那个失疯的父亲说过的疯话负责吗？
I sometimes think there's very little difference between him and you.
我有时觉得你和他之间没什么区别。
You've both insane. Bosie, the window.
你们都很疯狂，波西，关窗。
My God, I've had just about had as much as I can stand of this.
天呐，我已经受够了我能忍受的。
-Oh, my God.    -Is this the thanks I get
-哦，上帝。  -这就是我的回报。
-for devoting myself to you these past two years?  -My God!
-两年来，我把我自己献给了你。  -上帝啊！
What is happening to me?
我这是怎么了？
How I ever came to think you were so marvelous...
我曾认为你很非凡。。
-Bosie, for God's sake, go away. -Oscar Wilde, the great genius,
-波西，行行好，离开我。    -奥斯卡王尔德，这个伟大的天才，
the great wit.
伟大的智者。
Idol of society. And look at you sniveling like some kicked dog.
社会的偶像，看看你现在像一只被踢开的狗一样哭泣。
Do you think I'm going to let you end this so easily, Oscar?
你真的认为我会轻易地让你结束这一切吗？奥斯卡。
You're not going to throw me aside
你别想把我抛到一边
because you've no further use for me.
就因为以后我对你再也没有用处了。
You're not my father!
你不是我父亲！
Bosie, are you insane?
波西，你疯了吗?
Didn't you know? It runs in the family.
你知道吗？我们家都有这德性。
Bosie, put it down.
波西，放下刀。
Bosie, please!
波西，别！
How insignificant you look when you're afraid, Oscar.
当你害怕时，你看起来是多么渺小，奥斯卡。
I never thought you'd be afraid of me.
我从未想到你会怕我。
Oh, this place depresses me.
哦，着地地方太压抑了。
Oh, um...
哦
I don't suppose you could let me have some money to pay the cab, could you? I...
我不认为你会让我付马车钱，你能？我身上。。。
Oh, well.
好吧
Wait for me, will you?
等我一下吧？
Yes, ma'钬檃m.
是的，夫人。
Good afternoon, madam. Good afternoon, Arthur.
-下午好，夫人。   -下午好，阿瑟
Is Mr. Wilde at home?
王尔德先生在家吗？
Yes, he's working at the moment, madam.
是的，他这会儿在工作，夫人。
But Mrs. Wilde is in the front room.
王尔德夫人在前厅。
-Mrs. Leverson, madam.  -CONSTANCE: Ada!
-里弗森夫人到，夫人。   -康斯坦斯：艾达！
My dear, I hope you don't mind my just dropping in.
亲爱的，我希望你不介意我的拜访。
Of course not. Arthur, may we have some tea, please?
当然不会，我们一起喝下午茶吧，请！
Certainly, madam.
遵命，夫人。
How nice to see you. Good heavens, you're freezing.
Come and get warm by the fire.
到炉子边暖和一下。
I was just embroidering my birthday present for Oscar.
我正在给奥斯卡的生日礼物绣花。
Do you think he's going to like it?
你觉得他会喜欢这个吗？
Oh, I'm sure he will,it's most handsome.
噢，我想他一定会喜欢的，真漂亮。
Oscar has the most expensive tastes, even in the simplest things.
奥斯卡一直都有很昂贵的品味，即使对最简单的小物件。
How is Oscar?
奥斯卡怎么样了？
Oh, much better.
噢，他好多了。
He just needed looking after properly.
他就是需要被很好的照顾
What about Bosie?
波西呢？
That's all over now, thank God.
结束了，感谢上帝。
I can't tell you what it was like, Ada.
我都不知道该怎么向你说，艾达。
To have a woman come between yourself and your husband,
就像有个女人在你和你丈夫之间，
that's something a wife can understand.
那是一个妻子能体会到的。
But another man.
但是如有另一个男人。
OSCAR: Constance,is that Ada's voice I hear?
奥斯卡：康斯坦斯，我听到了艾达的声音？
Yes, it is, dearest.
是的，她来了，老公。
I must hide this, I don't want to spoil the surprise.
我必须把这个收起来，不想让他失去惊喜。
Ada, my dear.
艾达，我亲爱的。
You're looking wonderful, Oscar.
你看起来气色不错，奥斯卡。
Mm, what a delicious hat!
Mm，多么精致的帽子！
Constance, where's that bottle of champagne I've been hoarding?
康斯坦斯，我储存的那瓶香槟酒呢？
Oscar, you're not going to start drinking so early.
奥斯卡，才那么早你就要喝酒。
Of course I am. This is a celebration.
我当然要的，这值得庆祝一下。
You finished the play?
你完成了你的剧作？
The curtain fell on the third act of
大幕将在第三场后落下
The Importance of Being Earnest as the doorbell rang.
《不可儿戏》的开场铃响了。
I'll get the champagne.
我去开香槟。
Ada, your timing is impeccable.
艾达，你来的时机真好。
-Is it a good play?    -Quite extraordinary.
-这是一部好戏吗？  -那是相当的精彩。
Ada, I'm happier than I've been for years.
艾达，这几年来，我现在最高兴了。
I'm working. I'm seeing more of the children.
我乐于工作，我乐于和孩子们在一起。
Constance is a guardian angel.
康斯坦斯真是一个守护天使。
In fact, I believe I'm getting dull and bourgeois and very old.
实际上，我相信自己已经变得很沉闷，很市侩，也很老。
You miss him, don't you?
你在想他，是不是？
Yes.
是。
Sometimes when I see the sunlight on an evening sky
有时当我注视着落日余辉
or wander by the river and watch the dark waters,
或当我漫步在河边，并注视着黯淡的河水，
I seem to see him flitting by me in the darkness,
仿佛看见他从我身边掠过，又消失在黑暗中，
and then I feel terribly alone.
于是我又坠入可怕的孤独中。
Have you seen this?
这个你看了吗？
Couldn't find the champagne glasses.
找不到喝香槟的杯子。
It's been such a long time since we used them.
我们已经好久没用它们了。
Oscar, what on earth is it?
奥斯卡，怎么了？
Bosie's elder brother was killed yesterday in a hunting accident.
波西的兄长在一次狩猎事故被杀
（有传说是自杀，因他也是同性恋，与当时英国首相罗斯伯理有染）
Oh, how terrible.
哦，太可怕了。
That would be Francis,wouldn't it?
他就是弗朗西斯，是吧？
Bosie was very fond of him, wasn't he?
波西很喜欢他，是他吧?
-Arthur.  -Sir?
-阿瑟。  -先生？
I want you to go to the post office presently and send a telegram.
我要你亲自去趟邮局，拍封电报。
Very good, sir.
好的，先生。
I think he may need me.
我想他可能需要我。
For as much as it has pleased Almighty God
为了尽可能地让万能的上帝得到满足
to take unto himself the soul of our dear brother departed,
请带走我们死去的亲爱兄弟的灵魂上天堂
we therefore commit his body to the ground.
我们现在埋葬他的身体于地下。
Well...
那么。。。
It would seem it takes a death to bring about
看来只有死亡才能给
a family reunion in this house.
这个家族带来凝聚。
You're all very silent.
你们都不说话。
I've just lost a son.
我已经失去一个儿子。
Doesn't that mean anything to any of you?
你们这样是不是太残忍了？
Hmm?
You're his mother. Don't you weep for your son?
你是他的母亲，你不想为你的儿子哭泣吗？
The only real male son you ever bore.
你生下的唯一的有男子气的儿子。
-Really, Father...   -The only real man among the three of you!
-事实上，父亲。。。   -你们三个中唯一一个真正男人！
Goodbye, Mother.
再见，母亲。
Goodbye, Bosie.
再见，波西。
Bosie!
波西！
Where the devil do you think you're going?
魔鬼将要带你去哪里？
I've buried my brother.
我已经埋葬了我的兄弟
There's nothing to keep me here any longer.
没有什么事情让我再在这里呆下去了。
This is your home, damn you!
这是你的家，混蛋！
You belong here!
你属于这里！
You were born here!
你生在这里！
Kinmount has been the House of Douglas for more than 300 years.
道格拉斯家族在金芒特已经有300年了。
-Goodbye, Percy.  -Bosie!
-再见，珀西。  -波西！
Bosie.
波西
Don't go, boy. Stay here.
别走，小子，呆在这里。
Just for a few days, eh?
只待几天，好吗？
It gets so lonely here sometimes and...
有时这里会非常冷清，而且。。。
Well, just for a few days, eh, Son?
那就，呆几天，儿子?
You call me son?
你叫我儿子？
I'm not your son.
我不是你的儿子。
You disowned me, or had you forgotten?
你否认过我，你忘了吗？
You disowned me just as you've disowned the whole family.
你否认过我就像你否认过整个家庭。
You drove Mother out of this house
你把母亲赶出了这座房子
with your abuse and your immorality.
用你的辱骂和你的恶行。
You persecuted me until I had to keep away from you
你骚扰我，使我不得不离开你
for fear of what I might do if I were here to lay hands on you.
我害怕如果我在这里再住下去，我会对你下什么样的狠手。
I tried to make a man out of you.
我试着让你变成一个男人。
I tried to protect you against yourself.
我试着教你保护你自己。
It's no more than any other self-respecting father would do.
这只不过是任何一个自尊的父亲都会这样做的。
You lost your self respect the day you threw my mother out of this house
你把我母亲抛出这所房子那天你就失去了自尊
and brought your mistress here to live with you.
那天你还把你的情妇领进门和你同居。
-Damn your insolence! -Please!
-拿你的傲慢无礼去见鬼吧！  -别这样！
I ought to take a whip and thrash you to the ground.
我就应该拿鞭子把你抽倒在地。
I would welcome the opportunity, believe me.
我希望有这样的机会，相信我
You talk to me of the moral issue.
你敢和我谈道德。
-For heaven's sake,   -Father!
-天呐，  -父亲！
Well, what about him and that damned Wilde fellow?
那他自己又怎么样？还有他那该死的伙伴王尔德？
Thank God I succeeded in putting an end to that.
感谢上帝，我已经结束了他们的关系。
One of these days you'll get down on your knees
总有一天，你会跪在地上
and you'll thank me for it.
感谢我为你做的这一切。
He sent me a telegram this morning.
他今天早上还给我发了份吊唁电报。
At least he has more sympathy with my bereavement than you seem to have.
至少他对我丧失亲人的的同情比你多
I'm going back to London this afternoon, and I warn you,
我今天下午会伦敦。我警告你
if ever you try and interfere in my private affairs again,
如果你再试着干涉我私人的事情，
I'll buy myself a pistol and I'll hunt you down and kill you.
我将买把手枪，追到你并杀了你。
Bosie!
波西！
You're no son of mine, do you hear?
你再也不是我的儿子了，你听到了吗？
You're not my son!
你不是我的儿子！
Go back to your precious friend,
滚回到你那珍爱的朋友身边吧，
but, I warn you, I haven't finished with you yet!
但是，我警告你，我和你没完！
Or him!
和他也没完！
I'll see you both behind bars!
我将把你们两个送监！
Do you hear?
听到了吗？
Behind bars!
送监！
I have a great deal to make up to you for, Oscar.
我有很多话要跟你说，奥斯卡。
I've been perfectly horrible to you in the past.
我过去完全对不住你了。
No, don't mention it anymore.
不，别在提那些了。
Sometimes it takes a good row to clear the air.
有时，一次激烈的争吵会消除误会。
What are we going to do about your father?
你打算怎么对付你父亲？
Believe me, it's only because of you
相信我，这都是为了你
that I haven't taken some sort of legal action against him.
我才没有对他提起诉讼。
And involve your whole family in a scandal?
也是为了不让整个家族陷入丑闻吧？
That wouldn't help anybody except perhaps the journalists.
这对任何人没有好处，只会便宜了那些狗仔记者。
Just so long as he leaves me alone, that's all.
只要他不管我的事，仅此而已。
Good heavens, what are we talking about my father for?
天呐，我们干嘛谈我的父亲？
Your new play opens on Saturday.
你的新剧星期六上演。
We should be drinking to its success.
我们需要为成功干杯。
Its success?
成功了？
My dear boy, you don't doubt it'll be a success, do you?
哥们儿，你不认为它会成功吗？
To The Importance of Being Earnest.
为《不可儿戏》干杯。
To the importance of friendship.
为友谊干杯。
伦敦圣詹姆斯剧院
隆重上演
《不可儿戏》
-Wait there.   -Yes, sir.
在这里等着。  -是的先生。
Lord Queensberry, sir?
昆斯博里侯爵大人？
Yes.
是我。
I'm sorry, sir, I've strict instructions not to let you into the theater.
对不起，大人，我有严格的命令不允许你进入剧院。
You must be out of your senses.
你一定是疯了吧。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
Who the devil are you anyway?
你他妈的是什么人？
I'm a police officer, sir.
我是一个警官，先生。
Are you indeed?
真的?
Police officer, are you?
警官，你吗？
Are you?
你是吗？
Don't forget the cripple, sir.
可怜一下我这个瘸子吧，先生。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
No unauthorized persons are permitted to enter the theater.
没有得到允许的人不许进入剧院。
Do you realize who you're talking to?
你知道你在和谁讲话吗？
Oh, I do indeed, Your Lordship.
哦，我知道，侯爵大人。
Now look here, My Lord, why don't you run along and forget the whole thing?
您看啊，我的大人，您为什么不离开这里忘掉这一切呢？
You don't want to go in there and spoil everybody's enjoyment.
你其实不想进入这里去破环大家的雅兴。
I'm not completely without influence.
我不是完全没有影响力的人。
I'm quite sure you're not, My Lord.
我知道你不是，我的大人。
No, I shall report you to your senior officer, sir.
不，我将向你的上级控告你，警官。
Bit loose in the upper story, wouldn't you say, sir?
你会向上级通融一下吧，长官？
Hmm.
Well, let's hope that's the last we've seen of him tonight.
但愿这是今晚我们最后一次看到他。
Ladies and gentlemen, I have enjoyed this evening immensely.
女士们先生们，今晚我非常的高兴。
The actors have given a charming rendering of a delightful play.
演员们的迷人表演使得这部剧非常令人愉快。
And your appreciation has been most intelligent.
而你们也表现出很智慧的欣赏力。
I congratulate you on the success of your performance,
我祝贺你们双方的表现都取得了成功，
which proves to me
这向我证明了
that you think almost as highly of the play as I do.
你们对这部剧的思考有着和我一样的高度。
-That's quite a wit...   -Cab!
-太有趣儿了。。。  -马车！
There's Queensberry.
那是昆斯博里。
Queensberry? What's he up to?
昆斯博里？他要干什么？
Mad as ever, I suppose.
我猜他像以往那样要疯。
Mad.
发疯。
QUEENSBERRY: Excuse me! Excuse me!
昆斯博里：让一下！让一下！
Mr. Wilde, may I present you with this, sir?
王尔德先生，我能送你这个吗？
How charming.
好迷人。
Every time I smell them, I shall think of you, Lord Queensberry.
每当我闻见它们的味道，我就会想到您，昆斯博里侯爵。
The Albemarle Club.
去阿尔比马尔俱乐部（王尔德是会员）
Hurry. Hurry!
快点，快点！
Can I help you, sir?
我能帮你吗，先生？
Give me a pen.
给我一支笔。
Now, I want you
现在，我要你
to give this message
把这便签
to Mr. Oscar Wilde.
给奥斯卡王尔德先生。
Very good, sir.
尊办，先生。
致奥斯卡 王尔德:
表演的像个鸡奸者。
Here you are, Edward.
给你，爱德华。
Thank you, Mr. Wilde, sir.
谢谢，王尔德先生
-Good morning, Wilde.   -Congratulations!
-早上好，王尔德。    -恭喜成功！
-Thank you.     -Cab!
-谢了。   -马车！
Wilde, my dear fellow.
王尔德，我的老伙计。
Saw your play last night. Laughed myself sick.
昨晚看了你的剧，把我笑惨了。
You seem to have made a remarkable recovery, Major.
看来你已经有了显着的恢复，少校
Oh, Mr. Wilde. A gentleman left this for you last night, sir.
哦，王尔德先生，一位绅士昨晚给您留下这个。
-Oh.  -I hear your play was a big success, sir.
-噢。   -我听说你的演出很成功，先生。
Congratulations, if I may say so.
祝贺您，先生
Thank you, Sydney.
谢谢你，西德尼。
Hello, old chap. Enjoyed your play...
你好，老伙计，喜欢你的演出。。。
Well, there's no doubt, Mr. Wilde,
王尔德先生，这无疑
on the basis of what is written on this card alone,
基于这张卡片上所写的，
you have the strongest possible grounds
您有足够的理由
for an action against Lord Queensberry for criminal libel.
对昆斯博里侯爵提起文字中伤的诉讼
Does that mean, Sir Edward, that you will take the case?
这就是说，爱德华爵士，您将接手这个案子？
Well, the question is, of course,
那么，问题是，当然，
do you want to proceed with this action?
您是否要进行诉讼？
Well, of course!
当然要！
Why do you ask that, Sir Edward?
您为什么要问这个？爱德华爵士。
Well, no doubt, Queensberry's defense
那么，毫无疑问，昆斯博里的辩护
will be that the libelous statement complained of
将会是他的文字诽谤的观点的抱怨缘由
was justified and in effect true.
是否是合理公正的和有效真实的
It most certainly isn't true.
它显然不是真实的
Nevertheless, the defense will make every effort to prove that it is,
不过，他们的辩护将努力证明它是真实的，
and that could be extremely embarrassing for Mr. Wilde.
而这将使得王尔德先生很难堪。
I agree. Oscar, it simply isn't worth it.
我同意，奥斯卡，这样不值得。
Queensberry's obviously a lunatic.
昆斯博里显然是个疯子。
To take an action against him is exactly what he wants.
对他进行诉讼正是他想要的。
That's why he left that card.
这就是他为什么要留下这张纸条。
But if we let him get away with this,there'll be no holding him.
但是，如果让他这么逃脱，那就没什么阻挠他下一步的了。
We have to draw a line somewhere. It's a matter of principle.
我们必须明确界限，这是原则问题。
I'm afraid Lord Alfred is right.
我认为阿尔弗雷德爵士是对的。
The man must be stopped somewhere.
必须得有什么能够阻止这个人。
Then you wish to proceed with this action?
那么你将进行诉讼了？
I do.
我要。
Can't wait to see my father's face when I go into the witness box.
当我进入证人席，真想看看我父亲是什么狼狈相。
When I tell...
当我告诉。。。
You're not going into the witness box, Bosie.
你不会进入证人席的，波西，
Are you mad, Oscar?
你疯了吗，奥斯卡？
I've only got to tell them how he's...
只有我才能告诉大家他是。。。
How he's persecuted me these past two years,
过去两年中，他是怎么迫害我的，
how he drove my mother out of the house with his insane ravings.
怎么用疯话把我的母亲赶出那座房子的。
I'm not having you involved, Bosie.
我不想让你卷进来，波西。
I'm afraid, Mr. Wilde, that Lord Alfred is already involved.
王尔德先生，我恐怕，阿仁弗雷德爵士已经卷进来了。
Well, of course I'm involved.
那么，当然，我也就卷进来了。
I'm not having you exposed to more scandal than is necessary.
不到万不得已的时候，我不会让你曝光更多的绯闻。
Oscar, don't you realize...
奥斯卡，难道你没有意识到。。。
Bosie, you're not going into the witness box and that is final.
波西你不会进入证人席，就这么定了。
You'll have to forgive Bosie. He's a little impulsive.
你要原谅波西，他有点冲任性。
So it would seem.
好象是的。
Anyway, you have a very strong case, Mr. Wilde.
不管怎么样，王尔德先生，你将有一场很激烈的官司。
What's the matter, Robbie?
谁在乎呢，罗比？
Are you determined to bring about your own destruction, Oscar?
你这个决定将给你自己带来毁灭，奥斯卡？
Is that what you've trying to do?
这是你将要做的吗？
I don't understand.
我不明白。
I used to think you had a mind of your own.
我过去曾经认为你有自己的想法。
A great mind. Oh, really.
很伟大的思想，哦，真的。
Oscar, you mustn't let Bosie push you into this thing.
奥斯卡，你不能让波西把你推入这些事情。
-What's the alternative?    -Go abroad.
-那该怎么躲开呢？  -出国去。
Let Queensberry and his son fight their quarrel without you.
让昆斯博里父子互相斗争，而你置身其外。
They've well-matched.
他们俩旗鼓相当。
It's too late, Robbie.
这太晚了，罗比。
Well, Sir Edward, I'm entirely at your disposal.
好吧，爱德华爵士，我将随时听后你的吩咐。
Any further information you need?
你还需要什么更多的信息？
There is one question I feel compelled to ask.
有一个问题，我不得不问。
Please do.
请讲。
I can only accept this brief, Mr. Wilde,
我只接受这个简要声明，王尔德先生，
if you assure me on your honor as an English gentleman
如果你以一名英国绅士的名誉向我保证
that there is no truth in the charges made against you.
那就是，所有对你的指责都不是真实的。
I assure you as an Irish gentleman
作为一个爱尔兰绅士，我向您保证
that there's no truth whatever in any of them.
他对我的任何指责都是不真实的。
Well, then, shall we say here tomorrow morning at 10:30, Mr. Wilde?
那么，我们将在明天上午10：30这里继续谈，王尔德先生？
Good. Mr. Humphries.
好的，汉弗莱先生。
Paper! Queensberry arrested!
报纸！昆斯博里被捕了！
Paper! Paper! Special edition!
报纸！报纸！报纸！号外！
Queensberry arrested!
昆斯博里被捕！
Paper! Paper, sir! Paper!
报纸！报纸，先生！报纸！
COURT USHER: Silence!
庭警：肃静！
That's Edward Carson, defending Queensberry.
那是爱德华 卡森，昆斯博里的辩护律师。
（卡森被誉为北爱尔兰无冕之王，一战时任海军大臣和不管大臣，最终，当上英国上诉法院院长）
We went to Trinity College together.
我们一起在（牛津的）三一学院上过学
No doubt he'll perform his task with all the added bitterness of an old friend.
无疑，他将要完成给他老朋友增加痛苦的任务。
COURT USHER: Silence!
庭警：肃静！
Be upstanding in court.
庭上诸位，起立。
All persons who have anything to do
所有庭审有关的人员
before My Lords, the Queen's justices of oyer and terminer
面对效忠女王陛下的，中央刑事法庭的法官大人，
（位于伦敦老区的老贝利街，如今对游客开放）
and general gaol delivery for the jurisdiction of the Central Criminal Court,
该大人拥有听审权，终判权和收监权
draw near and give your attendance. God save the Queen.
尔等趋近就席，专心听询作答。天佑吾王。
Put up John Sholto Douglas, Marquis of Queensberry.
带约翰·肖托·道格拉斯，昆士贝里侯爵 上庭
John Sholto Douglas, Marquis of Queensberry.
约翰·肖托·道格拉斯，昆士贝里侯爵
Are you John Sholto Douglas, Marquis of Queensberry?
你是约翰 肖尔特 道格拉斯，昆斯博里侯爵？
I am, sir.
正是我，大人。
"The jurors for Our Lady, the Queen, upon their oath present
“女王陛下的陪审团，将依据他们所发的誓言，对以下起诉书列举的：
"that John Sholto Douglas, Marquis of Queensberry,
针对约翰·肖托·道格拉斯，昆士贝里侯爵
"contriving and maliciously intending to injure one
“所犯的图谋恶意伤害
"Oscar Fingal O'Flahertie Wills Wilde,
奥斯卡·芬达尔·奥弗莱赫蒂·威尔斯·王尔德，
"and to excite him to commit a breach of peace,
“并涉嫌激怒原告去扰乱治安
"and to bring him into public contempt, scandal and disgrace,
并在大庭广众下给原告带来蔑视，丑闻和羞辱，
"did on the 14th day of February in the year of our Lord 1895,
时间是在1895年2月14日
"and within the jurisdiction of this court
“同时，本庭的诉法审判权还包括，对以下所列举的
"unlawfully, wickedly and maliciously write and publish
"非法，恶意和蓄谋书写和公布
"a false and scandalous,
“一个虚构的和诽谤的
"malicious and defamatory libel, in the form of a card,
“恶意的和破坏名誉的文字诽谤物，以一张便签纸的形式，
"directed to the said Oscar Fingal O'Flahertie Wills Wilde,
直接用说话的形式交给，奥斯卡·芬达尔·奥弗莱赫蒂·威尔斯·王尔德，
"on which were written the words,
“在上面写着如下字样，
"'To Oscar Wilde, posing as a sodomite.'”?
“致奥斯卡 王尔德，表演地像个鸡奸者”
COURT USHER: Silence in court.
庭警：肃静。
"To the great damage, scandal and disgrace
“给原告造成了极大的伤害，丑闻和耻辱
"of the said Oscar Fingal O'Flahertie Wills Wilde
“即给奥斯卡·芬达尔·奥弗莱赫蒂·威尔斯·王尔德
"and against the peace of our said Lady the Queen, her crown and dignity,
“并且扰乱了在女王陛下的王权和尊严统治下的和平，
"John Sholto Douglas, Marquis of Queensberry,
“约翰·肖托·道格拉斯，昆士贝里侯爵
"upon the aforesaid indictment, how do you plead?"
“基于以上起诉书所列举的种种行为，你要怎么申辩？”
Guilty or not guilty?
有罪还是无罪？
Not guilty, My Lord.
无罪，大人。
If it please you, My Lord,
如果它能令您满意，大人，
it is my client's plea that the alleged libel
这是我的委托人对所谓诽谤行为的申辩
according to the natural meaning of the words thereof
按照字面上的原始意思
is true in substance and in fact,
在本质上和实际上都是真实的，
and that it was for the public benefit and interest
它是符合公众的利益和兴趣的
that the matter contained in the alleged libel should be published.
所以，这件所谓的文字诽谤物应该被公布。
Such a plea has been filed with this court?
这个的辩解庭上是否已经记录在案？
It has, My Lord.
已经记录了，我的大人。
Thank you, Mr. Carson. Let the jury be sworn.
谢谢你，卡森先生，让陪审团宣誓吧。
Take the Bible in your right hand and read from the card.
右手持圣经，按照卡片上念誓词。
"I swear by Almighty God that I will well and truly..."
“向全能的上帝发誓，我将很好地并真实地。。。”
I put the card in an envelope,
我把便签放进一个信封，
which I addressed to Mr. Oscar Wilde
在上写了：给奥斯卡 王尔德先生
and when Mr. Wilde came into the club,
当王尔德先生来到俱乐部，
I handed it to him saying that Lord Queensberry had asked me to give it to him.
我把信封交给他，并说这是昆斯博里侯爵要我把这个给他的。
And did you look at this card when Lord Queensberry gave it to you?
当昆斯博里侯爵给你便签时，你是否看到了上面的文字？
I did, sir.
我看到了，大人。
Thank you, Mr. Wright.
谢谢，赖特先生
I have no questions, My Lord.
我没有问题了，大人。
COURT USHER: The witness may stand down.
庭警：证人可以退席。
I don't think there's any suggestion by the defense
我不认为辨方律师有任何提示
that Lord Queensberry did not leave this card at the Albemarle Club,
能表明昆斯博里侯爵没有在阿贝马勒俱乐部留下这张便签
nor that he wrote upon it the words complained of by my client.
也没有写下使得我的当事人抱怨的文字。
In his plea of justification
在他的释罪申辩中
in which the defendant seeks to malign the character of Mr. Oscar Wilde,
被告竭力诋毁奥斯卡王尔德先生的品格，
the defendant put in evidence a letter
被告把一封信作为物证
written by Mr. Oscar Wilde to Lord Alfred Douglas,
这封信是由奥斯卡王尔德先生写给阿尔弗雷德道格拉斯爵士，
the son of the accused.
也就是被告的儿子。
I now propose to read the letter to the court, My Lord.
现在我打算把它读给庭上，大人。
"My own boy, your sonnet is quite lovely,
“我的宝贝男孩，你的十四行诗是如此的可爱，
"and it is a marvel that those red rose leaf lips of yours
“你的红玫瑰花瓣般的嘴唇，令人惊奇地
"should have been made no less for music of song than for madness of kisses.
“奏出与疯狂接吻一样乐曲
"Your slim guilt soul walks between passion and poetry.
“你的纤细负罪心灵行走在激情与诗歌之间。
"I know Hyacinthus, whom Apollo loved so madly,
“我知道，被阿波罗疯狂爱恋着的雅辛托斯（希腊神话中的一个形象）
"was you in Greek days.
“就是在希腊是的你。
"Always with undying love, yours, Oscar."
“对你的爱致死不休，你的奥斯卡”
The words contained in that letter may appear somewhat extravagant
在信中的词句会显得太过放纵
for those normally engaged in the writing of commercial correspondence.
这当然是对那些从事正常商业信函写作的人来说。
Silence!
肃静！
But Mr. Wilde is a poet
但是王尔德先生是一个诗人
and that letter is considered by him to be a prose sonnet,
而这封信经过他的深思熟虑，变成了一首散文诗。
and one in which he is no way ashamed.
在其中他一点也没有什么值得羞愧的。
I now ask Mr. Oscar Wilde to go into the witness box.
我现在要求奥斯卡王尔德先生入证人席。
Take the Bible in your right hand and read from the card.
右手持圣经，按照卡片上念誓词。
"I swear by Almighty God that the evidence I give to this court
“我向全能的上帝发誓，我带给法庭的证据
"shall be the truth, the whole truth, and nothing but the truth,
“将是真实的，且全部真实的，且没有不真实的，
"so help me God."
“上帝保佑。”
You are Mr. Oscar Wilde and you are the prosecutor in this case.
你是奥斯卡王尔德先生，也就是本案的起诉人。
I am.
我是。
How old are you, Mr. Wilde?
你多大了？王尔德先生？
I'm 39.
我39岁。
Are you married, Mr. Wilde?
你结婚了吗？王尔德先生？
I am, and I have two children, one aged nine and the other eight.
结了，且我又两个孩子，一个9岁另一个8岁。
And when did you first become acquainted with Lord Alfred Douglas?
你什么时候认识阿尔弗雷德道格拉斯爵士的？
In 1891.
在1891年。
A friend brought him to my house.
一个朋友带他来我家。
And since that time you have become close friends?
从那时起，你们就成为密友了？
He was a guest at my house many times.
他来我家做客好几次。
A guest of yourself and your wife?
他是你和你夫人的宾客？
Certainly.
当然。
In March 1893,
在1893年3月，
did it come to your notice that a letter addressed by you to Lord Alfred Douglas
你有没有注意到有一封你写给阿尔弗雷德·道格拉斯勋爵的信
had come into the hands of a certain person?
到了某个人的手中？
Yes, a man named Wood came to me
是的，一个叫伍德的人来找我
and said that he'd found it in a suit of clothes belonging to Lord Alfred.
他说在阿尔弗雷德的衣服里找到这封信。
Did he demand money for that letter?
他为了这封信是否向你要钱了？
He said a man had offered him 60pounds for it.
他说有人想出60英镑买这封信。
And what did you say to that?
那你对他说什么了？
I said I'v never received so large an amount
我说，我从未花费过那么一大笔钱
for a prose work of that length,
为了那么短的一首散文，
and I advised him to sell it to the man at once.
我建议他立刻卖给那个想要的人。
Prior to this time, you had been subjected to considerable annoyance
在这件事情之前，你是否还受到了相当多的
by Lord Queensberry, had you not?
来自昆斯博里侯爵的骚扰？有过吗？
Oh, yes.
哦，有过。
He's written several abusive letters to myself and my friends
他几次写那种带有辱骂的信，寄给我本人和我朋友们
and on one occasion, he forced his way into my house
并有一次，他堵在我家门口
and I was compelled to eject him.
而我不得已驱逐了他。
And what took place on that occasion?
后来又发生了什么？
He made certain accusations about my relationship with Lord Alfred
他很确信地指责我和他儿子阿尔弗雷德爵士的关系
and I said to him,
而我跟他说，
"Lord Queensberry, do you seriously accuse your son and me of improper conduct?"
“昆斯博里侯爵，你是很认真地指责你儿子和我的不正当关系吗？”
And what did he say to that?
那他又说了什么？
He said,"I don't say you are, but I say you look it."
他说:“我没说你们是，但我说你们看起来是。”
Silence in court!
肃静！
If there is the slightest disturbance again,
有谁再发出一点动静，
I shall have the court cleared.
我要把他请出法庭。
Mr. Wilde, your attention has been drawn to certain statements
王尔德先生，你的注意力已经被吸引到一个明确的陈述
made in the plea of justification
再加上由被告，昆斯博里侯爵
filed by the defendant, Lord Queensberry,
提交的释罪申辩
with reference to different persons impugning your conduct with them.
那就是已经有不同的人利用它们来对你的行为进行谴责。
Yes.
是的。
Mr. Wilde,
王尔德先生，
is there any truth whatever in any of those accusations?
在这些谴责中有没有任何符合事实的成分？
None whatever in any of them.
一点儿都没有。
Thank you, Mr. Wilde.
谢谢你，王尔德先生。
Mr. Wilde, you stated earlier that your age was 39.
王尔德先生，你刚才说你的年龄39岁。
-Is that correct?  -Yes.
-对吗？  -是的
You were born in 1854. That makes you over 40, doesn't it?
你出生在1854年，那就是说你已年过四十，对不对？
Oh, very well.
噢，正是。
Hmm.
At what age was Lord Alfred Douglas when you first met him?
当你第一次遇见阿尔弗雷 德道格拉斯爵士时，他多大岁数？
He was between 20 and 21.
他那时是在20到21之间。
Not yet 21. Hmm.
还不到21岁，对吧。
And since that time you have been close friends?
自从那时起，你俩就成为密友了？
Yes.
是的。
You've stayed with him at many places?
你和他一起去过很多地方？
Yes.
是的。
At Oxford, Brighton, on several occasions?
是不是去过几次牛津，布莱顿？
Yes.
是的。
And at various hotels in London?
在伦敦还住过各种旅馆？
Yes.
是的。
You've also been abroad with him several times.
您还有几次和他一起出国。
Yes, to Egypt, Paris and Monte Carlo.
是的，去过埃及，巴黎和蒙特卡罗（法国尼斯附近的赌城）。
One could therefore describe your friendship as intimate?
人们可以用亲密来描述你们之间的关系吗？
Yes, very.
是的，合适。
Indeed.
真的。
I have here a magazine called The Chameleon,
我手头有一本名叫变色龙的杂志
in which is an article by yourself.
在上面登有你的一篇文章。
Also, two poems contributed by Lord Alfred Douglas.
上面还有，阿尔弗莱德 道格拉斯爵士贡献的两首诗。
Yes, I thought them exceedingly beautiful.
是的，我想他们一定很精彩。
Did you?
是吗?
Do you remember the titles of these two poems, Mr. Wilde?
您还记得这两首诗的名字吗？王尔德先生。
Yes. One was called In Praise of Shame,
是的，一首叫巴黎的耻辱
and the other, Two Loves.
另一首叫，两个情人。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
These two loves, they were two boys, weren't they?
这两个情人，他们是两个男孩，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
One boy calls his love true love and the other boy calls his love shame.
一个男孩管他的情人叫真爱而另一个男孩管他的情人叫耻辱。
That is correct.
正确。
Do you think that made any improper suggestion?
你不觉得他们有不合适的暗示吗？
No, not at all.
没有，一点儿都没有。
Hmm.
There's another article in this magazine
这本杂志里还有另一篇文章
entitled The Priest and the Acolyte. Have you read that?
名叫牧师与侍从，你读过吗？
I have.
读过。
Did you consider that this article was in any way immoral?
你认为这篇文章有伤风败俗之嫌吗？
It was worse. It was very badly written.
这就更不对了，它只是写得不好而已。
Was it not the story of a priest who fell in love with an altar boy?
它是不是讲一个牧师陷入与祭台侍童的爱情的故事？
Well, I read it only once and nothing would induce me to read it again.
好吧，我只是读过一遍，没有什么吸引我再读它。
Do you think the story blasphemous?
你认为这个故事是亵渎神明吗？
I think it violates every artistic canon of beauty.
我认为它违反了每一条美学的艺术标准。
That is not an answer.
这不是回答。
That's the only answer I can give.
这是我可以给出的唯一答案。
I wish to know whether you thought the story blasphemous?
我希望知道你是否这个故事亵渎神明？
It disgusted me, and the end was completely wrong.
它让我恶心，且结尾完全不对。
Will you answer the question?
你将回答提问吗？
Did you or did you not consider the story blasphemous?
你是否认为它亵渎神明？
I thought it was horrid. Blasphemous is not a word of mine.
我对它很反感。亵渎神明不是我的用词。
I see.
我明白了。
Now, from the same magazine here
现在，从同一本杂志中
are some of the phrases and philosophies for the use of the young
有一些用于年轻人的短语和哲学观点
which you contributed.
是你贡献出来的。
"Wickedness is a myth invented by good people
“邪恶是由好人们构筑出来的神话
"to account for the curious attractiveness of others."
“用于解释别人的古怪的吸引力”
Do you think that true?
你认为这是真实的吗？
I rarely think anything I write is true.
我很少认为我写的都是真实的。
"Religions die hard when they are proved to be true."
“宗教信仰很难被湮灭，当它们被证明是真的。”
Is that true?
这是你写的吧？
Yes, I hold to that,
是的，我坚持这点，
but it's too big a question to go into here.
但这个论题太庞大了，在这里很难深入讨论下去。
Did you think that was a safe axiom
你认为这是可靠的公理
to put forward for the philosophy of the young?
用于向年轻人中作为哲学观点提出？
I think it's most stimulating.
我认为它很刺激。
"If one tells the truth, one is sure sooner or later to be found out."
如果一个人讲真话，他迟早会被发现的
（《不可儿戏》中原文：我的人生经验是，每当你撒谎，你便在各方面得到巩固。当你讲真话，你便被遗弃在一个孤独而痛苦的位置，且没有人相信你半句。）
A pleasing paradox, but I do not set very much store on it as an axiom.
多么令人愉悦的悖论，可惜我对这种格言的储备不多。
Whether moral or immoral?
那它们是道德的还是不道德的？
There is no morality or immorality in thought.
在思想中就没有什么道德不道德。
There are immoral emotions.
这就是不道德的情感。
Quite so.
正是如此。
Now then.
那么。
This is the introduction to your book, The Picture of Dorian Gray.
在你的小说《道林格雷的肖像》有这样一段引言。
"There is no such thing as a moral or immoral book.
“从来就没有什么道德或不道德的书。
"Books are well written or badly written."
“书只有写得好与不好。”
That expresses your view?
它表达了你的观点？
My view on art, yes.
我对艺术的观点，是的。
Then no matter how immoral a book may be, if it is well written,
如果一本书写得好，就不管它有多么不道德，
it is in your opinion a good book.
这是你对一本好书的观点。
If it is well written so as to produce a sense of beauty.
如果它被写得产生了美感。
Then a well written book
那它就是一本好书
putting forward perverted moral views may be a good book?
提出一个歪曲道德标准的观点也能算是一本好书？
A work of art doesn't put forward views.
艺术作品从来不提出观点。
Views are for people.
观点是有由人们提出的。
A perverted novel might be a good book?
一本堕落的小说会是好书吗？
I don't know what you mean by a perverted novel.
我不知道你怎么定义堕落的小说。
Then, I will suggest The Picture of Dorian Gray
那我就提示《道林格雷的画像》这本书
as being open to the interpretation of being such a book.
作为这类书公开存在的解释
Only to brutes and illiterates.
只是对畜生和文盲。
The affection and love of the artist for the youth, Dorian Gray,
艺术家为年轻人展现的情感和爱情，比如像道林格雷这样，
might lead an ordinary individual
会引导一个普通个体
（书中道林格雷做出很多不道德的事情）
to believe that it might have a certain tendency.
去相信这会是一个必然趋势。
I have no knowledge of the views of ordinary individuals.
我不知道普通个体的观点，
Hmm.
I propose, if I may, to quote
我打算，如果可以，引用
a few passages from this book.
书中一些段落。
The artist Hallward is speaking to Dorian Gray.
艺术家霍尔沃德对道林格雷说
（书中人物，给道林画像的艺术家）
"It is quite true that I have worshiped you
“千真万确，我非常地崇拜你
"with far more romance than a man usually gives to a friend.
“我对你怀有一个男人对他的朋友更多的浪漫之情。
"I have never loved a woman.
“我从未爱过一个女人。
"From the moment I met you,
“自从见到你的那刻起
"your personality had the most extraordinary influence over me.
你的个性就最强烈地影响着我。
"I quite admit I adored you madly, extravagantly, absurdly."
“我不得不承认我疯狂地，放肆地，荒唐地仰慕你。”
Do you mean to say that that passage
你是否想说那个段落
describes the natural feeling of one man towards another?
描写了一个男人对另外男人的自然的感情？
Dorian Gray's was a remarkable personality.
道林格雷有着非常显着的个性。
May I take it that you as an artist have never known the feeling described here?
这里我是否可以把你当成（书中的）那个艺术家，你从来没有体验过这里描述的感觉?
No. It is a work of fiction.
不，它是虚构的作品。
Let us go over it phrase by phrase.
让我们逐字逐句地看。
"I quite admit that I have adored you madly."
“我不得不承认我疯狂地仰慕你。”
What do you say to that? Have you ever adored a young man madly?
这你怎么说？你曾经疯狂地仰慕一个年轻人吗？
I've never given adoration to anyone.
我从来没有仰慕过任何人。
Except myself.
我自己除外。
I suppose you think that a very smart thing?
我猜那是一件很好玩的事？
Not at all.
一点也不。
"I have adored you extravagantly."
“我已经挥霍无度地仰慕你。”
Do you mean financially?
你是要说财务上的吗？
Oh, yes, financially!
噢，是的，财务上的！
Do you think that we are talking about finance?
你认为我们现在是在谈论财务？
I don't know what you've talking about.
我不知道你在谈论什么。
Don't you?
你不知道？
Then I hope that I shall make myself very plain before I have done.
那么，我希望在说完之前就把话说得明白些。
And we come now to the letter which you wrote to Lord Alfred Douglas.
现在我们来谈谈你写给阿尔弗雷德·道格拉斯勋爵的信。
It begins, "My own boy."
开头就是，“我的宝贝男孩."
Now, why should a man of your age address a young boy
看那，为什么你这样年龄的男人称呼一个比你
nearly 20 years younger as "My own boy"?
年轻20岁的男人为“我的宝贝男孩”？
I was fond of him. I've always been fond of him.
我喜欢他，我一直都喜欢他。
Did you adore him?
那你仰慕他吗？
No, I like him.
不，我喜欢他。
And that's not an ordinary letter.
那不是一封普通的信件。
You might as well cross examine me
你或许可以像盘问我一样
as to whether a Shakespeare sonnet was improper.
去盘问莎士比亚的十四行诗是否得体。
Suppose a man who was not an artist had written this letter.
设想一下，如果一个非艺术家的男人写下这样一封信
Would you say that this was a proper letter?
你是否会认为它是一封得体的信吗？
A man who was not an artist wouldn't have written that letter.
一个不是艺术家的男人也写不出这样的信。
Well, I can suggest, for the sake of your reputation,
那么，我就提示一下，为了你的名誉考虑，
that there're nothing very wonderful in this.
在这封信里也没什么特别精彩的。
"Those red rose leaf lips of yours..."
“你的红玫瑰花瓣般的嘴唇。。。”
It largely depends on how it's read.
这封信主要是取决于怎么去读它。
"Your slim guilt soul walks between passion and poetry."
“你的纤细的愧疚心灵行走在激情和诗歌之间。”
Is that a beautiful phrase, Mr. Wilde?
这是一个很优美语句吗？王尔德先生。
Not as you read it, Mr. Carson. You read it very badly.
不是您这样读的，卡森先生，你读得太糟糕了。
I do not profess to be an artist, Mr. Wilde.
我可不是什么职业艺术家，王尔德先生。
And when I hear you give evidence,
当我听说有证据显示你是，
I've very glad that I am not.
我很高兴我不是。
My Lord, I don't think mylearned friend should talk like that.
大人，我认为不该以这种方式与我博学的朋友谈话。
May I suggest, Mr. Carson,
我能提示一下吗？卡森先生，
that you do not air your personal opinions in this court?
你在法庭上不该公开发表你个人的观点。
It is very difficult, My Lord.
这很困难，大人。
JUDGE: Yet nevertheless.
法官：尽管如此也不行。
Where did you first meet the man Wood, Mr. Wilde?
你第一次遇见那个叫伍德的男人是在什么地方？王尔德先生。
He came to my house. I think it was in January of 1893.
他来到我家。我想是在1893年1月。
And on the same evening, you took him out to supper?
就在同一个晚上，你带他去吃晚饭？
Yes.
是的。
Did you consider that he's come to levy blackmail?
你是否想过，他是来向你索取敲诈金的吗？
I did, and I was determined to face it.
我想过，而且我决定要面对这件事。
By taking him out to supper and giving him 40pounds?
以带他出去吃晚饭，还给他40英镑的方法吗？
Well, I saw that the letter was of no value,
其实，我当时认为那封信没那么值钱，
and I gave him the money after he told me a pitiful tale
而我给他钱，是因为他告诉我一个可怜的故事
about being out of work.
关于他失业的故事。
I suggest that you had immoral relations
我提示，你们有不道德的关系
with him first and then gave him the money.
第一次见面，就给他钱。
My Lord, I really must protest
大人，我真的要提出抗议
at my learned friend's method of questioning the witness.
抗议这种，提问我博学的朋友的方式。
I do not see that Mr. Carson is in any way out of order.
我没有看到卡森先生有扰乱次序的方式。
Thank you, My Lord.
谢谢您，法官大人。
Do you know a man named Charles Parker, Mr. Wilde?
你认识一个名叫查尔斯帕克的男人吗？王尔德先生。
The witness will answer the question.
证人要回答问题。
Yes, he was a friend of Lord Alfred's.
是的，他是阿尔弗雷德勋爵的朋友。
And a man named Atkin?
还有一个叫阿特金的人?
Yes, he was a friend of Parker's.
是的，他是帕克的朋友。
A man named Grainger?
还有一个叫格林杰的男人？
Yes, he was a manservant of Lord Alfred's.
是的，他是阿尔弗雷德勋爵的仆人。
And Taylor, Mr. Wilde. Do you know anyone called Taylor?
还有泰勒，王尔德先生。 你认识叫泰勒的人吗？
Yes, I have been to parties at his house. We...
是的，我去过他家的聚会。 我们。。。
Were all these, with the exception of Taylor, young men of about 20?
除了泰勒，所有这些人都是20岁左右的年轻人吗?
I like the society of young men.
我喜欢和年轻人交往。
Have you given money to any of them?
你给过他们中的任何一个吗？
I may have.
我也许给过。
Or presents?
礼物呢？
A silver cigarette case for Mr. Taylor,
给泰勒先生的一个银质香烟盒，
gold-topped walking stick for Mr. Parker,
给派克先生的有镀金头的手杖，
a book for Mr. Wood inscribed, "To Alfred from Oscar."
一本给伍德先生的书，上题写，“给阿尔弗雷德，自奥斯卡。”
Did you know, Mr. Wilde,
以下这些你知道吗？王尔德先生，
that Wood had been unemployed for three years,
伍德先生已经失业三年了，
that Parker was a valet, and that the man Taylor was also out of work?
帕克是个男仆，而那个叫泰勒的人也没工作。
That would not have affected my friendship with them.
那这也不影响我和他们的友谊啊。
And yet you gave them presents and entertained them to supper on diverse occasions.
可你却送他们礼物和在不同的场合请他们吃晚饭。
No doubt you drank wine and champagne.
无疑你们喝了红酒和香槟。
Iced champagne is a favorite drink of mine,
冰镇香槟是我最喜欢的饮料，
much against my doctor't orders.
却违背了我的医生的嘱咐。
Never mind your doctor's orders.
不管医生的嘱咐。
I never do.
我从不。
And at these supper parties
在晚餐聚会上
your guests no doubt had plenty of champagne.
你的宾客肯定是畅饮香槟。
I didn't press them to drink.
我从不强迫他们喝酒。
You did not stint them?
那你有没有限制他们？
What gentleman would stint his guests?
一个绅士会限制他的客人吗？
What gentleman would stint his valet and a groom, Mr. Wilde?
什么样的绅士会限制他的男仆和马夫呢？王尔德先生。
My Lord, I really must protest at my learned friend's sneering remarks.
法官大人，我抗议我的博学朋友被这样嘲笑戏弄。
Mr. Carson, I suggest you confine yourself to questions, not opinions.
卡森先生，我提示你，限定在你的问题，而不是你的观点。
Very well, My Lord.
好的，法官大人。
Did you know, Mr. Wilde,
你知道吗，王尔德先生，
that Taylor, Atkin and Parker
泰勒，阿特金和帕克
had been arrested in a raid on a house in Fitzroy Square?
在对菲茨罗伊广场一所房子的洗劫中被捕。
Yes, I read about that.
是的，我在报纸上读到过。
You know that they were charged with felonious practices?
你是否知道他们被控以重罪？
I understand that the magistrate dismissed the charge.
据我了解，地方法官驳回了控告。
About the young man Grainger.
关于那个叫格兰杰的年轻人。
Have you ever dined with him?
你是否曾经和他一起吃过晚饭？
No, never.
不，从没有。
But you know him?
但你认识他？
Yes, he was a manservant at Lord Alfred's house in Oxford.
是的，他是阿尔弗雷德勋爵在牛津时的家仆
So you saw him on several occasions?
所以你几次见到他 ？
I stayed in the house on several occasions.
因为我几次去过勋爵的房子。
Grainger waited at table.
格兰杰在旁伺候。
Did you ever kiss him, Mr. Wilde?
你是否亲吻过他，王尔德先生?
Oh, dear, no. He was extremely ugly.
哦，天呐，不，他太丑了。
Is that the reason you did not kiss him?
这就是你没有亲他的原因吗？
Mr. Carson, you are very insolent.
卡森先生，你太无礼了。
Did you say that you never kissed him?
你是说，你从没有亲过他吗？
It's a foolish question.
这是一个愚蠢的问题。
Then why, sir, did you mention that this boy was extremely ugly?
那么为什么，先生，你刚才是否说过这个男孩很丑？
I don't know why I mentioned that he was ugly
我不知道为什么我说他很丑
except that you stunned me with your insolent remark
除非你的无礼之举已经深深地击晕了我
and the insulting way you're treated me during this hearing.
还有，在这场庭审中你对我的侮辱方式。
Why did you mention his ugliness?
为什么你要说他丑陋？
It was simply that I...
这很简单，因为我。。。
Why? Why? Why?
为什么？为什么？为什么?
"I didn't kiss Grainger because he was ugly."
"我没有亲格兰杰是因为他很丑。"
Quite untrue... I protest, My Lord, at his accusations.
他的指控不合情理。。。我抗议，法官大人。
My learned friend puts words into the witness's?mouth.
我的博学朋友是作为证人发言的。
The witness is putting words into his own mouth.
证人已经亲口说出了这些话。
-I object.     -I will not have this brawling between counsels.
-我反对。   -我不想再发生律师之间的争吵。
If I may say so, My Lord,
我可以这么说吗？法官大人，
my learned friend has no right to make suggestions of a certain behavior
我的博学朋友已经没有对他的某种行为做出提示的权利
with a group of persons not represented in this court
就因为一帮没有出庭的人
and whose evidence we have not heard.
而随之而来的证据我们却从未听说过。
But you will hear it, Sir Edward.
但是你会听到的，爱德华爵士。
It is my intention to produce every one of the persons mentioned here
我打算把这里提到的每一个人
just now in this courtroom tomorrow morning.
明天上午都带到法庭来。
Wood, Parker, Atkin, Grainger and Taylor
伍德，帕克，阿特金，格林格和泰勒
will relate their loathsome experiences at the hands of the witness.
他们会把自己令人憎恶的经历与这位证人联系起来。
By your own admission, a group of blackmailers and police suspects, sir.
你要承认，这是一帮敲诈者和警方怀疑者，先生。
Nevertheless,they'll be here to give their testimony,
然而，他们会在这里给出他们的证词，
testimony that will prove my client's plea of justification
他们的证词将证明，我的当事人的释罪辩解
beyond any possible shadow of a doubt.
是没有任何疑问阴影的。
Silence in court.
肃静。
I think this would be an appropriate moment to adjourn.
我认为现在是休庭的合适时机。
The witness may stand down.
证人退席。
The court will reconvene at 10:00 a.m. tomorrow.
再次开庭定于明天上午10点。
Be upstanding in court.
全体起立。
All persons who have anything further to do
所有与本案下一步审理有关人员
before My Lords,the Queen's justices of oyer and terminer...
在面对陪审团，女王陛下的法官时。。。
Before this unfortunate trial started,
这场不幸的审判开始之前。。。
you gave me your word that there was no truth whatever
你向我保证他们的可怕指责
in any of these dreadful accusations.
无论如何都没有任何真实的成分。
I know, Sir Edward. It was unforgivably stupid of me,
我知道，爱德华爵士，我的愚蠢是不可饶恕的，
but I was afraid you wouldn't take the case.
我当时担心您不接受这个案子。
As it is,you realize you've already lost this case.
那现在，你应该意识到，官司已经输了。
But what is infinitely more serious
但事态严重性会扩大
is that when Carson puts these young men into the witness box,
当卡森把那几个年轻人带到证人席，
as he obviously intends to do,
他显然想要这样做，
their evidence will inevitably result in your being arrested
那几个年轻人的作证最终会导致你被捕
on some extremely grave charges.
而且你将背负几项非常严重的指控。
Sir Edward, may I just say one thing?
爱德华爵士，我可以说一件事吗？
Please do.
请讲。
The whole case started with my father accusing Mr. Wilde of carrying on an...
整件事情开头，是由我父亲指责王尔德先生与我
An immoral relationship with me, isn't that so?
有着不正当的关系，是吧？
Yes.
是的。
Then why in heaven't name can I not go into the witness box
那为什么我的名字没有被列入证人名单
-and deny this disgusting accusation?    -Bosie, for the last time.
-由我去否认这些令人恶心的职责？  -波西，最后一次。
-But it isn't true, Oscar.  -You know it isn't.
-但它不是真实的，奥斯卡。  -你知道啥呀。
Such a denial would undoubtedly add
这样的否认无疑会增加
considerable weight, Mr. Wilde.
有力的说服力，王尔德先生。
In my opinion, not to put Lord Alfred into the box would be a grave mistake.
以我看，不把阿尔弗雷德勋爵列入证人席是一个很严重的失误。
One that you might regret for the rest of your life.
一个让你后悔一辈子的失误
Gentlemen, I have infinite faith in the good sense of the common man,
先生们，我一直对好人有好报会有极大的信心，
and if, as you say, this case hangs
假如，像你们说的，这个案子被
on the evidence of paid informers
通过收买而来的证据所绞死
and criminals like Wood and Parker,
包括被像伍德和帕克这样的罪犯，
I cannot conceive that a British jury would take their word before mine.
我都无法想象那些不列颠的陪审员们在我面前怎么开口。
I wish I could share your faith.
我希望我也能有你一样的信心。
Well, what must be must be.
那么，该来的就让它来吧。
But I want you to understand that Lord Alfred is not
我想你会理解为什么不把阿尔弗雷德勋爵
to give evidence at this trial.
列入审判的证人席。
Very well.
好吧。
Well, I shall endeavor to salvage what is left of your reputation
那么，我将尽力挽救你还残存的名誉
by withdrawing from the case first thing in the morning.
上午要做的第一件事就是撤诉。
Incidentally, there's no need for you to be present in court tomorrow.
顺便说一句，明天你不用亲自到庭。
Indeed there's no need for you to be present in this country.
其实，你真的没有必要在这个国家出现。
There is a boat train leaving for Calais at 10:00 tonight, Mr. Wilde.
今晚十点有一趟开往加来的班轮，王尔德先生。
（法国城市，与英国隔海峡相望）
You're be well advised to be on it.
听我劝，你最好上船。
Before you condemn Lord Queensberry,
在你们判罪昆斯博里之前，
I ask you to consider whether the gorge of any father ought
我请求诸位思考一下，在这种情况下
not to rise in such circumstances.
是否该提倡吞噬生父这种行为
I ask you to bear in mind that Lord Queensberry's son
我请你们记住，昆斯博里侯爵的儿子
was so dominated by Wilde that he threatened to shoot his own father.
是受到王尔德的操控，而向自己父亲开枪的。
I now have a more painful part of the case to approach.
我现在已经接近到了这桩案子的最痛苦的地方。
It's my unhappy duty to bring before you young men...
我真不愿意把这几个年轻人带到你们面前。。。
-Did Wilde get away?    -No.
-王尔德先生逃了吗？  -不。
...to tell their miserable tales.
。。。告诉你们他们的痛苦遭遇。
I first call Charles Parker.
我首先召查尔斯帕克到庭。
May I claim Your Lordship's indulgence while I interpose
法官大人，我能不能冒昧地插断一下，
to make a statement, which is, of course,
做个声明，当然
made under a feeling of great responsibility?
这个声明也是在强烈的责任感驱使下做的？
By all means, Sir Edward.
当然可以，爱德华爵士。
Forgive me, Mr. Carson.
原谅我，卡森先生。
I'm sure it must be apparent to Your Lordship
我想法官大人您一定很明白
that those who represent Mr. Wilde in this case
那些在本案站在王尔德先生立场的人们
have before them a terrible anxiety.
面临着很恐怖的焦虑。
A verdict given in favor of the defendant Lord Queensberry
一个对被告，昆斯博里侯爵有利的判决
might be interpreted as conclusive proof as to the accusations of impropriety
会被演绎成指责伤风败俗的真凭实据
brought against the plaintiff, Mr. Oscar Wilde
而它是针对原告，王尔德先生的
and thus, we would be going through,
既然这样，我们可能会经受
day after day, an investigation of matters of the most appalling nature.
日复一日的调查，而真相会是令人震惊的。
Under these circumstances,
在这种情况下，
I feel I am not going beyond the bounds of my duty
我觉得我不会再继续的的职责
if I now interpose and say on behalf of Mr. Wilde
如果现在我为王尔德先生的利益调停
that I would ask to withdraw from the prosecution.
那么我将撤回起诉。
If that is your wish, Sir Edward, so be it.
如果这是你的意愿，爱德华爵士，那就如你所愿吧。
COURT USHER: Silence.
庭警：肃静。
And if I may say so in the circumstances,
在这种情况下，如果让我说的话，
I think you have made a wise decision.
我认为您做了个明智的决定。
Are you taking a cab? Yes, come on.
你还不快去叫辆马车？是的，马上。
Get this to the office as soon as you can.
你把这个尽可能快地送到办公室。
"Oscar Wilde withdraws from case."
“奥斯卡王尔德撤诉”
-Take a cab and hurry.   -Yes, sir.
-打辆车，快点。  -是的，先生。
Either the words complained of were justified or they were not.
不管这些抱怨的文字是否公正。
If they were, then the statement, "posing as a sodomite"
如果是，那么“表演地像个鸡奸者”的陈述
is true and the publication was for the public benefit.
就是真实的，而它的公布是符合公共利益的。
You will now consider your verdict.
你们现在考虑你们的判决。
We've already agreed upon a verdict, My Lord.
我们已经有了判决，法官大人。
The prisoner will rise.
被告起立。
Gentlemen of the jury, do you find
陪审团的先生们，你们是否查明了
the plea of justification has been proved or not?
释罪申辩已经被证明了,还是没有?
We do.
我们查明了。
And do you find the defendant guilty or not guilty?
那你们查明了被告是有罪还是无罪？
Not guilty, My Lord.
无罪，法官大人。
Silence in court! Silence! Silence!
肃静！肃静！肃静！
Usher, silence the court.
庭警，肃静。
Usher!
庭警！
Well, they haven't wasted any time.
这下，他们没有浪费任何时间。
Why, what do you mean?
什么，你什么意思？
A copy of the evidence has already been sent
证据的副本已被送达
to the Director of Public Prosecutions.
公诉检察官那里。
Bosie, for God's sake, stop walking up and down.
波西，看在上帝的份儿上，停止走来走去吧。
Oh.
哦。
Oh, you haven't eaten a thing, sir.
哦，你一点儿都没吃，先生。
I don't really want it.
我吃不下。
Thank you, Arthur.
谢谢你，阿瑟。
Oscar, I've just heard from one of the reporters.
奥斯卡，我从一个记者那里听说。
There's a warrant out for your arrest.
有一张你的逮捕令。
What about Constance and the children?
那康斯坦斯和孩子们怎么办？
I saw them off on the train myself.
我亲眼看着他们上了火车。
Thank you, Robbie.
谢谢你，罗比。
Oscar, I beg of you.
奥斯卡，我求你。
There's still time to catch the 10:00 train.
现在还来得及赶上10点的火车。
I have a cab waiting outside.
我有一辆马车等在外面。
You've wasting your time, Robbie.
你在耽误你的时间，罗比。
I've been trying for the past two hours.
过去两小时，我一直在劝他。
Oscar, will you please listen to me?
奥斯卡，你能听我的吗？
-It's too late.   -It's not too late, I tell you.
-太晚了。   -我告诉你，还不晚。
-Look, it's 9:35.   -Oh, Robbie, have a drink.
-看，现在9：35.  -噢，罗比，喝杯酒吧。
In three hours we can be in France.
三小时后我们就到法国了。
You look as if you need it.
看来是你需要离开。
-Mr. Wilde?   -Yes.
-王尔德先生？  -是的。
We're police officers. We hold a warrant for your arrest.
我们是警官，我们有一张你的逮捕令。
Really?
是吗？
I must ask you to accompany us to the police station.
我必须要带你去警察局。
Bosie, do something for me.
波西，替我做几件事。
Anything.
任何事都行。
Leave the country. If possible, tonight.
如果有可能，今晚就出国。
-I can't desert you.    -Bosie, please.
-我不能抛下你。  -波西，听我的。
Very well.
好吧。
So it's goodbye, hmm?
这就是告别吗？
-Oscar, I can't believe...    -Goodbye.
-奥斯卡，不敢相信。。。  -再见。
We'll come with you.
我们和你一起去。
-There'll be no need for that, sir.    -Thank you.
-没有必要，先生。    -谢谢你。
Why do you look at me like that?
你为什么那样看我？
It's not my fault.
这不是我的错。
I loved him just as much as you did.
我和你一样爱他。
Don't you think if there was anything I could have...
难道你不认为我会为他做任何事情。。。
You can do as Oscar says, Bosie.
按照奥斯卡的话去做，波西。
Leave the country.
出国。
And the sooner the better, I should say.
越早越好，我说的。
"Lord Queensberry is triumphant.
“昆斯博里侯爵胜利了."
"Mr. Oscar Wilde is damned and done forever."
“奥斯卡王尔德先生永远被诅咒。”
And about time.
时报怎么评论。
-"Public morality will be vindicated."   -Hear, hear.
-“公共道德将被维护."  -好，好。
"And this evil in our midst will, I hope, be removed forever."
“我希望，这种在我们中间的罪恶将永远被去除。”
Damn good thing, too. I never liked the fellow from the first.
这也太他妈的痛快了，我一开始就不喜欢这个家伙。
Couldn't stand his plays. Lot of immoral rubbish.
真受不了他的戏剧，里面有太多不道德的垃圾。
Damn it all, Bentley, the fellow hasn't been tried yet.
该死的，宾利，这家伙还没有被审呢。
Innocent until proved guilty and all that sort of...
If he's been in my regiment, sir,
如果他在我的团里，爵士，
he's have been lashed to a gun carriage and flogged.
他将被绑在炮架上挨鞭子。
These artistic chaps are all the same.
这些文艺青年都一个德性。
A lot of long-haired degenerates.
留着长头发的颓废派。
I think you fellows are taking the whole damn thing too seriously.
我认为你们哥儿几个把整个事情看得过份严重了。
Live and let live, that's what I say.
别理它们，把它们放一边，这就是我想说的。
Anyway, I don't care what they do
无论如何，我都不介意他们做什么
as long as they don't do it in the street and frighten the horses.
只要他们不在街上做，不吓到马就行。
All right.
好吧。
Do you want me to burn them, Mr. Brace?
你想让我焚烧书籍吗？布雷斯先生。
Good heavens, no. Fellow might get off.
上帝啊，不，那个家伙也许会免责。
Mr. Humphries.
汉弗莱斯先生。
Sir Edward.
爱德华爵士。
I... They didn't tell me that it was you.
我。。。他们没有告诉我这会是你们。
Mr. Wilde.
王尔德先生。
I don't know what arrangements you're made about your defense,
我不知道你为了你的辩护做了什么安排，
but if you wish it,
但是如果你愿意，
Sir Edward and I would be most happy to act on your behalf.
爱德华爵士和我将很乐意站为你代理。
Thank you, I'm...   I'm very grateful.
谢谢你们，我。。。 我感激不尽。
There are certain legal aspects of this case, Mr. Wilde,
这个案子里有一个确定的法律问题，王尔德先生
that have shocked me greatly.
这个问题是我很震惊。
The prosecution has based its entire case on the evidence of witnesses
控方在本案中举出的证人都被证明
who admitted crimes ranging from assault, petty larceny to blackmail.
他们承认犯有抢劫，小偷小摸和敲诈勒索。
Yet the Crown has no intention of prosecuting any of these witnesses.
而最高法院却没有打算，检控其中任何一个证人
They are to go scot-free.
他们都安然逃脱。
Such a state of affairs has profoundly shaken
居然会有这种事情发生，它极大地震撼了
my inherent faith in British justice.
我对不列颠法律公正的固有信心
In these circumstances, I would consider it an honor,
在这种情况下，我将为荣誉而战，
if you'll permit me to offer my services.
如果您愿意让我为您效劳。
Thank you.
谢谢您。
I'm afraid the cost of the other case is still unpaid,
我恐怕其他案件的费用还没有付清，
and I'm in considerable debt.
可我却欠了不少债。
Mr. Wilde,
王尔德先生，
Sir Edward and I are agreed that there is no question of a fee.
爱德华爵士和我都同意费用不是问题。
Thank you.
谢谢你们。
Well, there are many matters we should discuss, Mr. Wilde.
那么，这儿有很多问题我们要讨论，王尔德先生。
CLERK: Put up Oscar Fingal O'Flahertie Wills Wilde.
书记员：带奥斯卡·芬达尔·奥弗莱赫蒂·威尔斯·王尔德到庭
Oscar Fingal O'Flahertie Wills Wilde.
奥斯卡·芬达尔·奥弗莱赫蒂·威尔斯·王尔德
COURT USHER: Silence in court. Silence!    JUDGE: Order. Order.
庭警：肃静。肃静！   法官：秩序。秩序。
CLERK: Are you Oscar Fingal O'Flahertie Wills Wilde?
书记员：您是奥斯卡·芬达尔·奥弗莱赫蒂·威尔斯·王尔德 ？
I am.
我是。
Oscar Fingal O'Flahertie Wills Wilde,
奥斯卡·芬达尔·奥弗莱赫蒂·威尔斯·王尔德
you stand charged on 25 counts.
您有25项指控。
On the first count, the jurors for Our Lady, the Queen, upon their oath
第一项，由宣誓效忠女王陛下的陪审团
present that Oscar Fingal O'Flahertie Wills Wilde,
向法庭提交奥斯卡·芬达尔·奥弗莱赫蒂·威尔斯·王尔德
on 14th day of March in the year of Our Lord 1893,
于1893年3月14日
in the County of London and within the jurisdiction of this court,
在伦敦郡，在本法院的管辖范围内，
being a male person, unlawfully did commit acts of gross indecency
作为一个男人，涉嫌非法严重猥亵
with another male person, one Alfred Wood.
另一名男人，阿尔弗雷德 伍德
And against the form of the statuette in such case made and provided,
在这种情况下以伤风败俗的形式
and against the peace of Our Lady the Queen,
扰乱在女王陛下的
her crown and dignity.
王权和尊严治下的治安。
On the second count, the juries aforesaid...
第二项，前述陪审团。。。
...against the form of the statute in such case made and provided
以伤风败俗的形式
and against the peace of our said Lady the Queen, her crown and dignity.
扰乱女王陛下的王权和尊严治下的治安。
Oscar Fingal O'Flahertie Wills Wilde,
on the aforesaid indictments, how do you plead?
依前所述的指控，你有什么申辩的？
Guilty or not guilty?
有罪还是无罪？
Not guilty.
无罪。
My Lord, gentlemen of the jury,
法官大人，陪审团各位先生们，
the first nine counts in the indictment refer to the prisoner's misconduct
起诉书的前九项涉及犯人
with a young man named Alfred Wood.
与一名叫阿尔弗雷德 伍德的年轻男人的不端行为。
The next three to Frederick Atkin.
下面的三项涉及弗雷德里克·特金
Two to the man Taylor. Three to Charles Parker.
两项涉及泰勒。三项涉及查尔斯帕克。
And the last to Wilde's conduct with a lad named Shelley.
最后一项涉及王尔德与一名叫雪莉的小伙子的行为。
It will be shown that Wilde systematically endeavored
这都显示着王尔德一步一步地试图
to influence these young men's minds towards vicious causes.
影响着这些年轻人的思想，按照他的邪恶目的。
And to mold them to his own depraved will.
以他自己的腐化意愿去塑造年轻人。
Gentlemen of the jury, when you have heard the evidence of these men,
陪审团的先生们，当你们听到这些人的作证时，
I assure you that you will be justified
我保证你们会做出
in finding the prisoner guilty on all counts.
认定被告对各项罪名有罪的裁断。
I call first Alfred Wood.
我召第一个证人阿尔弗雷德伍德。
COURT USHER: Call Alfred Wood.
庭警：带阿尔弗雷德 伍德上庭。
Alfred Wood.
阿尔弗雷德伍德。
Take the Bible in your right hand and read from the card.
右手持圣经，按照卡片上的念。
"I swear by Almighty God that the evidence I give to this court
“我向全能的上帝宣誓，我给法庭的证据”
"shall be the truth, the whole truth and nothing but the truth,
“将会是真实的，全部真实的，没有不真实的，”
"so help me, God."
“上帝保佑我。”
In all my years at the bar, I cannot remember coming face to face
在我的法庭生涯中，不记得这种面对面
with such a miserable collection of witnesses.
痛苦地收集证据。
Wood, Parker, Atkin.
伍德，帕克，阿特金。
The prosecution must have scraped
公诉人一定是
the bottom of the barrel to get that lot together.
搜肠刮肚地想到把这些人凑在一起。
What I cannot understand is how a man of Wilde's taste and breeding
我想不到的是，像王尔德这样的品味和修养
can come to associate with such people.
居然和这些人搞在一起。
Well, to understand that, Charles,
你要明白，查尔斯，
you'd have to understand the nature of Wilde's perversion.
你不得不理解王尔德的反常本性。
And I'm a lawyer, not a doctor.
可我是律师，不是心理医生。
To me, it's loathsome, degenerate and unnatural.
对我个人来说，这也是令我讨厌的，堕落的和不正常的。
Yet I feel so sorry for him.
我对他也感到很遗憾。
It is a terrible thing, Charles, when a man of Wilde's talents and genius
这真是一件可怕的事情，查尔斯，当一个像王尔德这样有才华和天赋的人
is slowly crucified by a lot of blackmailers and common criminals.
逐渐被因为一些敲诈和普通犯罪而钉上十字架。
There's very little hope for an acquittal, is there?
是不是已经无望免罪了？
Well, the case has already been judged by the press and the public.
其实，这案子已经被新闻界和公众给判了。
As far as they're concerned, Wilde is guilty.
在他们看来，王尔德是有罪的。
It only remains for him to be sentenced.
对他来说，剩下的就是定罪。
The most we can hope for is that, out of this hysteria of prejudice and hatred,
我们最希望做的也就是，摆脱偏见和仇恨带来的歇斯底里，
there might shine a glimmer of Christian charity and forgiveness.
让基督的慈善和宽容再闪出一丝光芒。
Do I understand you to say then, Mr. Wilde,
我能这么理解吗？王尔德先生，
that there is no truth whatsoever in the evidence of Alfred Wood?
那就是阿尔弗雷德伍德所做的证词没有一点是真实的。
It's true that we had supper together,
我们一起吃晚饭是真实的，
but the accusations of impropriety are quite untrue.
但是不正当的指控一点都不真实。
Charles Parker, what part of his evidence is untrue?
查尔斯帕克，证词的哪一部分不真实？
He never came to the hotel with me.
他没有和我一起去宾馆。
He never had dinner with me and he never came to my room.
他没有和我一起吃晚饭，也从来没进过我的房间。
We had tea at the St. James's once, but all of the rest...
我们曾经在圣詹姆斯喝过茶，其他的。。。
Is untrue.
就不真实了。
Then, Atkin. What of his evidence?
那么，阿特金。他的证词呢？
My Lord, my learned friend seems to have forgotten
法官大人，我的博学朋友看起来已经忘了
that the witness Atkin perjured himself in the box.
证人阿特金曾经在他自己的案子上做伪证。
Your Lordship dismissed this witness for that reason.
法官大人因为这个原因取消了他的证词。
The witness's evidence was not struck from the record, Sir Edward.
证人的证词不受记录的影响，爱德华爵士。
In my humble submission, My Lord, it should have been.
我恳请法官大人收回成命。
That is for me to decide.
这是我的决定。
As Your Lordship pleases.
随大人的便吧。
What of Atkins's evidence, Mr. Wilde?
阿特金的证词呢？王尔德先生。
The accusations of indecency are quite untrue.
关于猥亵的指控很不真实。
In fact, these witnesses, according to you,
实际上，这些证词，照你说的，
have lied throughout the trial.
从庭审自始都是在说谎。
With remarkable ease.
他们太熟练了。
As an experienced writer and storyteller,
作为一个老道的作家和编剧，
I've lost in admiration of their inventiveness.
我已经对他们的创造力惊叹不已。
You seem also to have been lost in admiration for their youth, sir.
你看起来似乎更关心他们的年轻，先生。
I'm a lover of youth.
我爱好青年人。
Yes, we have gathered that.
是的，我们已经收集到了。
Now, let us turn to this publication, The Chameleon.
现在，让我们转向出版物，变色龙杂志。
My Lord, are we to be subjected to a further discourse
法官大人，我们下一步是否要讨论一下
on the literary morals of the defendant?
被告的文学道德？
I understood from my learned friend that he's going to confine himself
我从我博学的朋友那里了解到，他想自己界定
to the specific charges made in the indictment.
起诉书的专门指控
This is cross examination as to credit, My Lord.
这是对信用的盘查，法官大人。
I feel obliged to say that questions which learned counsel thinks
我不得不说一个博学的律师思考这个问题
should go to credit, he is entitled to put.
是应该的，他有资格进行下去。
I shall not keep you long, Mr. Wilde.
我不会持续很长时间的，王尔德先生。
I trust not, Mr. Gill.
我相信你不会，吉尔先生。
In this magazine, to which you made a contribution,
在你投稿的这本杂志里，
there appears a poem by Lord Alfred Douglas
刊登了一首艾尔弗雷德道格拉斯勋爵的诗歌
entitled Two Loves.
名字叫两个情人。
It contains these lines.
有几行是这样的。
"Sweet youth,
“亲爱的年轻人，”
"tell me why, sad and sighing,
“告诉我为什么悲伤和叹息，”
"does thou rove these pleasant realms?
“伴着你徜徉在快乐国度中？”
"I pray, tell me sooth. What is thy name?
“我恳求，告诉我实情。你叫什么名字？”
"He said, 'my name is Love.'
“他说，我的名字叫爱情”
"Then straight the first did turn himself to me
“然后第一个直接转向我”
"and cried, 'he lieth, for his name is Shame.
“并哭泣着说：他撒谎，因为他的名字叫羞耻。”
"'but I am Love, and I was to be alone in this fair garden,
“我才是爱情，而我在这个美丽的花园里却很寂寞，”
"'till he came unasked by night.
“知道他夜里冒昧闯进。”
"'I am true Love.
“我是真爱。”
"'I fill the hearts of boy and girl with mutual flame.'
“我用相通火焰撩拨着男孩与女孩的心”
"Then, sighing, said the other,
“随后，长叹一声，而另一个却说，”
"'have thy will,
“你要做什么，”
"'I am the love that dare not speak its name.'?
“我才是爱情，却不敢说出名字？”
And what, Mr. Wilde, is the love that dare not speak its name?
那么，王尔德先生，什么样的爱不敢说出名字？
The love that dare not speak its name, in this century,
不敢说出名字的爱，在这个世纪，
is such a great affection of an elder for a younger man.
是一个长者对青年的伟大情感。
As there was between David and Jonathan.
正如大卫和乔纳森之间的感情。
（出自圣经，两人之间心心相印，纯洁友爱）
Such as Plato made the very basis of philosophy
正如柏拉图奠定的哲学基础
and such as you will find in the sonnets of Michelangelo and Shakespeare.
正如你可以在米开朗基罗和莎士比亚的十四行诗中找到的一样。
It is a deep, spiritual affection
它是一种深深的，精神层面的情感
that is as perfect as it is pure.
它纯洁地近乎完美。
It is in this century misunderstood, so much misunderstood
在这个世纪，它被误解了，被误解到
that it may be called the love that dare not speak its name.
它都不敢说出它的名字。
And on account of it, I'm placed where I am today.
正是因为这样，我今天才被带到这里。
But it is beautiful,
但它是美丽的，
it is fine,
它是健康的，
it is the noblest form of affection.
它是情感的最高贵形式。
There is nothing unnatural about it.
这里面没有任何矫揉造作。
It is intellectual.
它是理智的。
And is repeatedly to be found between an elder and a younger man
它多次在长者和青年之间被发现
when the elder man has intellect and the younger man has all the hope and joy
因长者饱含智慧，而青年充满希望与快乐
and glamour of life before him.
在他面前是生命的魅力。
But it is so the world does not understand.
它不被这个世界所理解。
The world mocks at it.
这个世界嘲笑它。
And sometimes puts one in the pillory for it.
有时人们会把木枷套在它头上。
COURT USHER: Silence in court.
庭警：肃静。
Rubbish!
一派胡言！
Silence in court!  Sit down, sir!
肃静！坐下，先生！
If there is the slightest manifestation of feeling like this again,
如果再有谁表现出这样的情感，
I shall have the court cleared.
我将把他请出法庭。
I have no further questions, My Lord.
我没有问题了，法官大人。
JUDGE: The witness may stand down.
法官：证人可以退席。
That concludes the case for the prosecution, My Lord.
为公诉人做结案陈辞，法官大人。
May it please you, My Lord, gentlemen of the jury,
法官大人，陪审团的先生们，
this is a serious and grave question for you to decide.
这是一个非常严重的问题，需要你来决定。
And yours is a position of great responsibility.
你们的职位责任重大。
Now, a great deal of public feeling has been excited against Mr. Wilde
现在，公众对王尔德先生的不满情绪高涨
by the quotation of passages of poetry and literature
通过引用诗歌和文学段落的言论
and in particular from Mr. Wilde's book, The Picture of Dorian Gray.
特别是通过王尔德先生的小说，《道林格雷的肖像》
Now I ask you, members of the jury,
现在我问你们，陪审团的成员们，
is an author to be judged on the morals of the characters of his book?
要根据书中人物的道德标准来评判一个作家吗?
Was Stevenson accused of being a lustful and depraved monster
史蒂文森是否被指责为一个好色堕落的怪物
because he wrote Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde?
因为他写了《化身博士》？
As to the affection which Mr. Wilde expressed in his letters,
至于王尔德先生在他的信中所表达的情感，
he himself has described it as pure, true affection,
他自己曾把它描述为纯洁、真诚的爱
absolutely unconnected with and completely alien to the
绝对不能联系到，甚至完全不同于
filthy practices described in this court
在这个法庭上所被检方列举出的一帮罪犯
by the prosecution's band of criminals.
所描述的肮脏行为。
Mr. Wilde is not an ordinary man.
王尔德先生不是一个普通人。
He is a man who has written poetry and prose,
他是一个写过诗和散文的人，
brilliant dramas, charming essays.
还写过精彩的戏剧和迷人的短文。
He writes letters in a tone which to most of us may appear
他写信的语气，在我们大多数人看来，可能是
high-flown, inflated, exaggerated, even absurd.
高高在上、夸大其词、甚至是荒谬的。
But he's not ashamed or afraid to produce those letters.
但他并不羞于或害怕出示这些信件。
When a man comes forward with letters such as these and says,
当一个人拿着这样的信走上前来说，
"I do not shrink from the judgment of the world upon these productions,"
“我并不畏惧世界对这些作品的评判，”
has he not given the best proof of his innocence?
他没有给出他清白的最好证据吗?
Innocence, gentlemen of the jury, has courage and faith
陪审团的先生们，在人类最终的审判中，
in the ultimate judgment of mankind.
清白是需要有勇气和信念的。
As to the evidence of the youths, Parker, Atkin, Wood
至于帕克、阿特金、伍德这些年轻人的证据
and their associates,
还有他们的同伙。
I respectfully submit that no jury can find a man guilty
在他们有污点的证据下，我恭敬地断言，
on their tainted evidence.
陪审团无法判定一个人有罪。
It deepens one's horror to think the prisoner's freedom
一想到囚犯的自由就加深了人们的恐惧
is at the peril of such persons.
是冒着这样的危险的人吗
Before you consider this case, therefore,
因此，在你考虑这件事之前，
I implore you to let your judgment only be affected by those witnesses
我恳求你让你们的判决只受那些证人的影响
of whom you, as true and honorable men
那些说真话和高尚的证人
can say, with a clear conscience have given
只有他们，可以问心无愧地给出
true, honest and honorable testimony.
准确，诚实和可敬的证词。
And if, upon the examination of the evidence, you find it your duty to say
如果在审查证据时，你们发现有责任去说
that the charges against the prisoner have not been proved,
那些对被告的指控都是未被证实的，
I know you'll be glad that that bright reputation,
我想你们一定很高兴地看到，你们的鲜明的名誉
so nearly quenched in a torrent of prejudice,
在快要被偏见的激流浇灭的时候，
will have been saved by your verdict from absolute ruin.
又被你们的判决从绝对的废墟中拯救出来。
And that it will leave Mr. Wilde,a distinguished man of letters,
这将使王尔德先生，一位杰出的文学家，
to live a life of honor and repute
过上有荣誉和有声望的生活
and to give, in the maturity of his genius, gifts to our literature
在他的天赋成熟之时，给我们的文学以天赋的礼物
of which, already, he has shown such brilliant promise.
而且，它已经显示出灿烂的希望。
COURT USHER: Be upstanding in court.
庭警：全体起立。
Gentlemen of the jury, I understand that you are unable to arrive at a verdict.
陪审团的先生们，我知道你们无法作出裁决。
That is so, My Lord.
是这样的，法官大人。
Is there any prospect that if you retired
如果让你们再退下一会儿
and continued your deliberations a little longer,
继续你们的讨论
you'll be able to come to some agreement?
你们有希望达成一致的意见吗？
We have considered the question for three hours, My Lord.
这个问题我们已经深思熟虑了三个小时，法官大人。
And the only result we have come to is that we cannot agree.
结果却是我们不能达成一致意见。
Yes, I have no doubt that you have tried very hard
是的，我毫不怀疑你们已经非常努力用以
to come to some agreement, but on the other hand,
达成一至意见，但是另一方面，
the inconveniences of another trial are very great.
另一场审判结果对本案带来极大的麻烦。
My Lord, I fear there is no chance of an agreement.
法官大人，我恐怕没机会以达成一致意见。
JUDGE: Then, gentlemen, you are discharged.
法官：先生们，你们可以退席了。
FOREMAN: Thank you, My Lord.
首席陪审员：谢谢，法官大人。
My Lord, on the question of bail,
法官大人，关于保释的问题，
it may be some weeks before a retrial...
离重审此案还有几周时间。。。
Retrial! Retrial! Retrial! Retrial! Retrial! Retrial! Retrial!
重审！重审！。。。。。重审！
Hello, Robbie.
你好，罗比。
Mr. Wilde, we managed to raise bail.
王尔德先生，我们已经筹集到保释金了。
Come on, Oscar. Let me take you home.
走吧，奥斯卡。咱们回家吧。
Who put up the money for my bail?
是谁提供了我的保释金？
Bosie's brother Percy put up most of the money.
波西的哥哥佩西提供了大部分的资金。
Percy? How kind.
佩西？这么好心。
The rest was put up by the Reverend Headlam.
其余的部分由海德勒姆牧师提供。
5,000pounds in all.
一共5000英镑。
It's preposterous. A common felon would not be so heavily penalized.
太荒谬了。一起普通的重罪都要不了这么多罚金。
The Reverend Headlam? Mmm-hmm.
海德勒姆牧师？Mmm-hmm
Extraordinary! I hardly know him.
非常奇特！我几乎都不认识他。
-Oscar, let's go to a hotel.    -No!
-奥斯卡，让我们去住酒店吧。   -不!
ARTHUR: Mr. Wilde!
阿瑟：王尔德先生！
Mr. Wilde. Oh, sir, I've done everything I could.
王尔德先生。噢，先生，我已经做了所能的一切。
Your manuscripts. I've managed to save some of them,
您的手稿。我设法保存了大部分，
but they're been going through the house like vultures, sir.
但是他们像秃鹫一样把这房子搜查了一遍，先生。
AUCTIONEER: 20pounds! 25!
拍卖者：20英镑！25！
25pounds I've bid for this priceless first edition by Walt Whitman, whoever he may be.
25英镑，我对这本沃尔特惠特尼的首版诗集的出价，有谁更高
（美国诗人，《草叶集》作者）
Now, now, come along, gentlemen. Do I hear 30pounds?
快，快，快来，先生们。我是否听到了30英镑？
30pounds, 30. 35pounds.
30英镑，30.35英镑
35pounds, 35. Come along, we haven't got all night.
35 英镑，35。来吧，我们不能呆到整晚。
Going then at 30pounds. Going once, twice, three times.
就30英镑了。计数一次，两次，三次，成交。
Charles, the gent over there with the cigar.
查尔斯，那位抽雪茄的先生中标。
Now then. Hello, hello, hello. What have we got here?
那么现在，喂，喂，喂。我们搞到什么了？
A painting of the dear boy himself.
那个可爱男孩的自画像。
Very pretty, I'm sure. Very pretty.
非常可爱，我肯定。非常可爱。
Now what am I bid for this masterpiece? Do I hear 10 shillings?
现在，我是否该为这件大师作品出价10先令？
MAN: Ten shillings. AUCTIONEER: Ten shillings I'v bid.
男人：10先令。拍卖者：我已经标价10先令。
Do I hear a pound?
我是否听到1英镑？
-1pounds.    -1pounds!
-1英镑。   -1英镑！
1pounds, 1.
1英镑，一
Excuse me, ladies and gentlemen, I think we have company.
对不起，女士们先生们，我想我们有客人来了。
Perhaps His Eminence will bid for this artistic painting.
也许这位阁下想参与这件艺术品的竞标。
What about 30 bob, sir?
30先令怎么样，先生？
Come on, Oscar. Haven't you seen enough?
走吧，奥斯卡。你难道没有看够？
-No?
-不想？
Well, all right, then. Going at a pound. Going, going...
那么，好吧，接着进行，1英镑。接着，接着。。。
40 guineas!
40畿尼！
-AUCTIONEER: 40 guineas.
-拍卖者：40畿尼。
Well, then. Any advance on 40 guineas?
那么，有谁想超过40畿尼？
All right. Sold to His Lordship for 40 guineas.
好吧，卖给这位绅士40畿尼。
Charlie, give the gentleman his painting.
查理，把这幅画给这位先生。
-40 guineas.    -Thank you, My Lord.
-40畿尼。  -谢谢您，先生。
-Thank you.   -What are you going to do with it now you've bought it?
-谢谢你。  -您买下它打算拿它干什么？
Hang it in the bathroom!
把它挂在浴室！
Aw, blimey, governor. What a waste of 40 quid.
奥，天呐，长官。40英镑就这么浪费了。
MAN: I say, a little bit rash, what?
男人：我说，真有点鲁莽，什么？
I feel like a drink.
我想去喝一杯。
Excuse me, please.
请让一下。
Excuse me. Thank you.  Excuse me, madam.
让一下。谢谢你。让一下，夫人。
Excuse me. Thank you.
让一下，谢谢你。
Excuse me.
让一下。
Come on, Oscar.
走吧，奥斯卡。
AUCTIONEER: Well, we weren't very quick there.
拍卖者：好吧，我们可不会那么快结束。
We should have asked His Eminence to autograph a few books, eh?
我们应该请阁下在几本书上签名，嗯?
Now then, an original manuscript of that uproarious comedy,
现在，这出轰动一时的喜剧的原始手稿，
The Importance of Being Earnestby the late Oscar Wilde.
《不可儿戏》，奥斯卡王尔德近期作品。
-Now, then, do I hear 10pounds?
-现在，好吧，我听到10英镑？
Mr. Wilde.
王尔德先生。
I'm most dreadfully sorry about this, sir,
我很抱歉，先生，
but I'm afraid we must ask you to leave.
我想我你们必须离开这里。
Ask us to leave? But how dare you come up...
让我们离开？你怎么敢过来。。。
-I'm very sorry, sir.  -Don't you realize that Mr. Wilde's...
我很抱歉，先生。  -你不知道这位先生是奥斯卡王尔德。。。
It's all right, Robbie.
算了吧，罗比。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Remarkable, the sort of people they allow in here these days!
这也太显眼了，有些人这些日子也来这种地方！
-I thought it was a high-class place!
-我曾以为这是一个高等地方！
I think it's blooming disgusting.
现在我认为这有一股臭气。
Come on, my friends, drink up. Pay the bill, will you, Freddie?
来吧，我的朋友，干了，付钱，你行吗?弗雷迪。
Why, certainly, Q.
啥呀，当然行，Q。
Cab!
马车！
God bless you, Mr. Wilde.
上帝保佑你，王尔德先生。
Hello, Amy.
你好，艾米。
Knightsbridge, cabby.
去骑士桥，车夫。
Yes, sir.
是的，先生。
MAN 1: Blimey! It's raining!
男人1：天呐，下雨了！
QUEENSBERRY: Get my carriage.
昆斯博里：上我的马车。
So long, Oscar!
再见，奥斯卡！
Are we going to have a bit of sport then?
等会儿我们去消化消化食儿？
Yes, I think so.
是的，我也这么想。
MAN 2: Come on, there we go, let's get in.
男人2：来吧，我们走，上车。
Come on.
来吧。
Follow him. As fast as you can.
以你最快的速度跟上他。
MAN 2: Tallyho!
男人2：带劲儿！
By God, they're following us. The man must be mad.
上帝啊，他们在跟着我们。这人一定疯了。
I should have thought it was common knowledge by now, Robbie.
我还以为这已经是常识了呢，罗比。
Go faster, driver!
加快，车夫！
MAN 2: Tallyho!
男人2：带劲儿！
Faster, driver, faster!
快点儿，车夫，再快点儿！
MAN 2: Tallyho!
男人2：带劲儿！
This is madness. I'm going to walk. Stop the cab, driver!
这简直是疯狂，我要步行。停车，车夫！
Oscar, don't be foolish.
奥斯卡，别犯傻了。
I'm not going to put you through all this.
我不想把你牵扯进去。
Oscar, where will you be?
奥斯卡，你要去哪里？
-I'm going to my mother.   -Right.
-我去我妈那儿。   -好的。
Carry on, driver.
接着走，车夫。
Well, now, my old darling, where's your friend?
好了，现在，我的老伙计，你的朋友在哪儿?
Why are you doing this, Queensberry?
你为什么这么做，昆斯伯里?
Why are you hounding this man in this way?
你为什么这样纠缠着这个人?
Haven't you had your pound of flesh?
你没有得到你应得的那磅肉吗?
（借用莎士比亚《威尼斯商人》夏洛克花钱买仇人的肉）
You don't know me very well, do you, Mr. Ross?
难道你还不了解我吗？罗斯先生。
I'm not so easily satisfied.
我可不是那么容易满足的。
That's quite evident.
这显而易见。
Tell Wilde that I shall not be happy
告诉王尔德，我不会高兴的
until I see him under six feet of earth.
除非他被深埋在地下6英尺。
（习俗起源于1665年伦敦大瘟疫期间,为了防止病毒传播，尸体被埋时要至少埋在离地表6英尺的地下）
Six feet of earth, Lord Queensberry,
地下6英尺，昆斯博里侯爵，
puts us all very much on the same level.
那把我们都埋在同一深度。
I've not finished with him yet!
我和他没完！
I shall hound him until his dying day!
我要一直追到他死!
Until his dying day!
直到他死的那天！
Well, what now, Q? Is the hunt still on?
好吧，现在做什么，Q？猎狐继续吗？
（在2005年英国颁布法令，明文禁止已经风行了六百年的古老贵族运动——猎狐运动）
Let's go to The Savoy.
我们萨伏伊酒店。
Ah, let's go to The Savoy. Go to The Savoy.
啊，我们去萨伏伊，去萨伏伊。
Oscar!
奥斯卡！
Oscar, is that you?
奥斯卡，那是你吗？
Willie!
威利！
Dear darling Mother. Yes, what is it?
亲爱的妈妈，是的，那是什么？
Dearest Mother, you know you should have been an actress.
最亲爱的妈妈，你该去当个女演员。
I doubt if the great Sarah Bernhardt herself
我怀疑伟大的莎拉·伯恩哈特本人
（1844年10月23日出生于巴黎，1923年3月26日逝世于巴黎，是一位法国演员）
made a more imposing Lady Macbeth.
使麦克白夫人显得更加威严。
（改编自俄国备受争议小说，穷家少女被卖作庄园主人的媳妇，面对冷感的丈夫、刁难的家翁，她都默默哑忍）
But aren't you just a little premature to wear mourning?
但是你穿丧服是不是有点太早了?
Oscar isn't quite dead yet, you know.
你知道，奥斯卡还没有完全死。
They crucified him.
他已被钉在十字架上。
Now, Mother, if you're going to go on like this, I...
妈妈，如果你再这样下去，我…
Who's there?
谁在那里？
OSCAR: Willie, let me in, for God's sake.
奥斯卡:威利，让我进去，看在上帝的份上。
Willie, let me stay. Let me stay.
威利，让我待一会儿。让我待一会儿。
Or I shall die on the streets.
否则我就会死在街上。
Are you drunk?
你喝醉了？
Here you are.
拿着。
Is this my son?
这就是我的儿子吗？
Is this Oscar Wilde, cringing in the dark like a frightened animal?
这是奥斯卡·王尔德，像受惊的动物一样在黑暗中畏缩吗?
Mother, for heaven's sake!
妈妈，看在上帝的份上!
Stand up, sir.
站起来，先生。
Stand up and face them, sir!
站起来，面对他们，先生！
For God's sake, don't let them in, Willie.
看在上帝份上，别让他们进来，威利。
Willie, open the door.
威利，去开门。
My son is ready for them.
我儿子已经准备好了对付他们。
Robbie. Thank God you've come.
Robbie。感谢上帝，你来了。
Ada.
艾达。
-Robbie, what's to become of me? -It's all right.
-罗比，我怎么办呢?   -好吧。
Couldn't you have taken his coat off? He's soaked to the skin.
你难道不能把他的外套脱掉吗? 他全身湿透了。
He's ill. He should be in bed.
他病了。他应该在床上。
But he... He can't stay here, you know. Well...
但他……他不能呆在这里，你知道的。嗯…
I mean, it would be awkward, you see.
我的意思是，这会很尴尬，你知道。
There's been mobs hanging about in the street all day,
有一群暴徒整天在街上游荡，
and if they were to find out he was here,
如果他们发现他在这里
well, there's no knowing what they'll do.
没人知道他们会怎么做
My son is not afraid of them!
我儿子不怕他们!
He'll stand up and face them
他会站起来面对他们
like a true Irish gentleman.
像一个真正的爱尔兰绅士。
I can find him a bed at my house. Come, Oscar.
我可以在我家给他准备张床。来,奥斯卡。
Don't sit up too late, my son.
孩子，不要熬夜。
You need all the sleep you can get
你需要尽可能多的睡眠
in this terrible time we've all passing through.
在这可怕的时刻，我们都经历过。
Come on, Oscar.
来吧,奥斯卡。
I'm not thinking of myself, you understand.
我不是在为自己着想，你明白的。
He is my brother. But it's my mother.
他是我的兄弟。但那是我妈妈。
She's not very well and any sudden shock might...
她身体不太好任何突如其来的打击都可能…
The prisoner will rise.
被告请起立。
Gentlemen of the jury, have you agreed upon a verdict?
陪审团的先生们，你们有了一致的裁决了吗?
We have.
我们有了。
Do you find the prisoner at the bar guilty or not guilty?
你认为被告席上的被告有罪还是无罪?
Guilty, My Lord.
有罪，法官大人。
COURT USHER: Silence in court!
庭警：肃静！
And is that the verdict of you all?
这就是你们所有人的判决吗?
Yes. Guilty.
是的，有罪。
COURT USHER: Silence!
庭警：肃静！
Oscar Wilde, the crime for which you have been convicted
奥斯卡·王尔德，你被判决的罪行
is so bad that one has to put a stern restraint upon one's self
是如此的恶劣，以至于我真的不想让一个严于自律的人
to avoid describing, in language I would rather not use,
用语言来描述它，
the sentiments that must rise in the breasts of every man of honor
任何一个正直的人在听了庭审细节后
who has listened to the details of these terrible trials.
都会义愤填胸
That you have been the center of a circle
你位于一个圈子的中心，一个由
of the most terrible corruption among young men,
最无耻下流的年轻人组成的圈子，
it is impossible to doubt.
这是无可怀疑的。
And under the circumstances, I shall pass the severest sentence the law allows.
基于上述情况，我将依法严惩。
Although, in my judgment
尽管，在我看来
it is totally inadequate for a case of this sort.
这对于这种情况是完全不够的。
Sentence of the court is that you go to imprisonment
法庭的判决是你要坐牢
and be kept to hard labor for two years.
要服苦役两年。
COURT USHER: Silence!
庭警：肃静！
Be upstanding in court.
全体起立。
All persons having anything further to do before My Lords...
所有在陪审团各位面前还有事要做的人……
Come on, back! Back. Come on, back!
退后，退后，退后！
He'll get his hair cut now, won't he?
他是要被剃去头发吗？
在瑞丁监狱关押期间，王尔德酝酿完成《狱中书》和《瑞丁监狱之歌》两部诗集。
2016年，在该监狱举办了王尔德纪念展览
OSCAR: "I never saw sad men who looked with such a wistful eye
奥斯卡:“我从未见过悲伤的人用如此渴望的眼神看着我”
"upon that little tent of blue we prisoners call the sky,
“在我们囚徒所称的蓝色小帐篷上”
"and at every happy cloud that passed in such strange freedom by."
"看着每一朵快乐的云以这种奇异的方式悠悠飘过。"
My dearest, your hands.
亲爱的，你的手怎么了。
I've never been so idle and worked so hard.
我从未如此空闲，也未如此劳累。
Please, my dear, we have so little time.
好吧，亲爱的，我们没有多少时间。
Oh, Constance, I've waited all these months for you to come.
哦，康斯坦斯，这几个月来我一直在等你来。
I would've come before, Oscar, only...
我是该早点来，奥斯卡，只是。。。
I don't know, it's all been so confusing.
我不知道，这一切都太令人困惑了。
Why have you come now?
你现在为什么来了?
I have some bad news for you, Oscar.
奥斯卡，我有个坏消息要告诉你。
I didn't want you to hear it from anyone else.
我不想让你从别人那里听到。
Your mother...
你的母亲……
She's dead, Oscar.
她死了,奥斯卡。
There was no pain. She passed away in her sleep.
没有痛苦。她在睡梦中去世了。
I wish I could leave here in that way.
我希望我能这样离开这里。
No, Oscar, you mustn't say that. You must be patient.
不，奥斯卡，你不能这么说。你必须有耐心。
It's not patience that's needed here, it's apathy.
这里需要的不是耐心，而是冷漠。
And apathy is the most pitiful of vices.
而冷漠却是最可怜的罪恶。
Constance, I don't think I can survive another year of this.
康斯坦斯，我想我一年也活不下去了。
Oh, my dear. It's only the thought of the children
哦,我亲爱的。就是靠着想见孩子们的念头
that keeps me alive in these terrible months of waiting.
这让我在这几个月可怕的等待中活了下来。
How are they?
孩子们怎么样了？
They're well.
他们都很好。
It'll be Vyvyan's birthday soon.
维维安马上要过生日了。
-Oscar, I...  -Is he 9 or 10?
-奥斯卡，我。。。  -他9岁还是10岁生日？
The time passes so slowly.
时间过得如此之慢。
Oscar, I cannot allow you to see the children again.
奥斯卡，我不能让你再见孩子们了。
I'm only trying to do what I think is right.
我只是在做我认为正确的事。
I've thought and thought about it and I...
这件事我思来想去，我。。。
Forgive me, my dearest.
原谅我，我亲爱的。
Please. Forgive me.
请原谅我。
Oscar.
奥斯卡。
I brought you some cigarettes
我给你带烟来了
and some delicacies, some chicken.
和一些好吃的，一些鸡肉。
I know what the food must be like.
我知道食物应该是什么样的。
Goodbye, my dear.
再见，亲爱的。
Will he have time to catch the boat train?
他有时间赶上渡轮火车吗?
If we hurry.
如果我们赶紧。
Goodbye, Mr. Wilde, sir.
再见，王尔德先生。
Goodbye, Dick. Thank you.
再见，迪克，谢谢你。
Thank you, my dear.
谢谢你，我亲爱的。
Oscar.
奥斯卡。
Come on, we must hurry.
来吧，我们得快点。
You look well, Oscar.
奥斯卡，你看起来气色不错。
The children send their love.
孩子们向你问好。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
I told them you were very ill. I hope you understand.
我告诉他们你病得很重。我希望你能理解。
Yes, of course.
是的,当然。
Well, I suppose we're better get down to business.
好了，我想我们最好开始谈正事。
There isn't very much time.
时间不多了。
I've arranged with my lawyer to pay you 150pounds a year.
我和我的律师约定每年付给你150英镑。
It's not much, I'm afraid, but it's all I can afford.
虽然不算多，但恐怕我也只能付得起这些了。
I am very grateful to you, Constance.
非常感谢你，康斯坦斯
Only I'm sorry I had to make one condition.
很抱歉，我必须提出一个条件。
If you see or communicate with Bosie again, the payments will stop.
如果您再见到波西或与他联系，付款将停止。
Yes, I... I understand.
是的，我。。。我能理解。
I know that may sound harsh,
我知道这听起来有些刺耳，
but I promise you I'm doing it to help you.
但我向你保证，我这么做是为了帮助你。
Hmm.
嗯。
Porter.
行李员
-Boat train, sir?   -Yes.
-渡轮火车？先生。  -是的。
Ada.
艾达。
You look lovelier than ever.
你看起来比以前更可爱了。
Oh, it's good to see you, Oscar.
噢，很高兴见到你，奥斯卡。
Ticket, madam?
票,夫人?
The gentleman has them. Thank you.
那位先生有。谢谢你。
Oh, Robbie, I can't bear to see him looking so ill.
哦，罗比，我不忍看到他病得这么厉害。
I was talking to the prison doctor yesterday.
我昨天和狱医谈过了。
Another six months in there and he's never come out alive.
再在那里待六个月，他就再也没能活着出来。
Constance.
康斯坦斯。
I want you to remember this.
我希望你们记住这一点。
I have always loved you, and I always will.
我一直爱着你，将来也永远爱着你。
You talk as if... You're going to get well again
你说得好像…你会好起来的
and you'll forget about these past two years.
你会忘记过去的两年。
You'll start work again.
你会重新开始工作的。
I know you too well, Oscar. Once you start writing, you...
奥斯卡，我太了解你了。一旦你开始写作，你……
Ada, don't be so depressed on my behalf.
艾达，别为我这么沮丧。
What better reward for one's sins than to be exiled to Paris?
还有什么比流放到巴黎更好的罪过奖赏呢?
Where no doubt I shall die as I have lived, beyond my means.
毫无疑问，我将那样死去，穷困潦倒，入不敷出。
What a gorgeous hat.
多漂亮的帽子啊。
Oh, Oscar.
哦,奥斯卡。
Goodbye, my dear.
再见,我亲爱的
Take care of the children.
照顾好孩子。
Hello, Oscar.
你好,奥斯卡。
I never understood it, Ada.
我一直不明白，艾达。
I just never understood it.
我就是不明白。
OSCAR: "Yet each man kills the thing he loves.
奥斯卡:“然而每个人都杀死他所爱的东西。”
节选自《雷丁监狱之歌》
"By each let this be heard.
“让每个人都听到这句话。
"Some do it with a bitter look,
“有些人一脸苦相地去做，
"some with a flattering word.
“有些人阿谀奉承地去做。
"A coward does it with a kiss,
“懦夫用吻来做，
"the brave man with a sword."
勇士拿剑来做。”